<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xml:lang="en-US" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/" xmlns:s="http://jadedpixel.com/-/spec/shopify">
  <id>https://www.yogi-bare.com/blogs/find-your-y-b.atom</id>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.yogi-bare.com/blogs/find-your-y-b"/>
  <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://www.yogi-bare.com/blogs/find-your-y-b.atom"/>
  <title>Yogi Bare USA - Find Your Y &amp; B</title>
  <updated>2021-08-13T06:30:01-05:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Yogi Bare USA</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.yogi-bare.com/blogs/find-your-y-b/a-yoga-routine-to-relieve-tennis-elbow</id>
    <published>2021-08-13T06:30:01-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-08-13T06:30:01-05:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.yogi-bare.com/blogs/find-your-y-b/a-yoga-routine-to-relieve-tennis-elbow"/>
    <title>A Yoga Routine To Relieve Tennis Elbow</title>
    <author>
      <name>James Oakley</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">If you’re a fanatic tennis player, the chances are high that you have experienced tennis elbow yourself. Tennis elbow occurs often in tennis players and is a painful condition that will affect your performance on the tennis court. Did you know that practicing yoga can actually help to relieve pain if you have a tennis elbow? By doing gentle stretching and easy yoga poses, athletes have experienced a relief in pain, which helped them to get back into shape and perform better on the tennis court. </span></p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">What is tennis elbow?</span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Tennis elbow is a form of </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">tendinitis, which is an inflammation or irritation of thick bands that connect your bones to your muscles in the elbow area. Even though it is called ‘tennis elbow’, you can actually get this painful condition if you haven’t even been playing tennis. The reason why it’s called tennis elbow is because this is a common condition among tennis players. The most common causes of tennis elbow are:</span></p>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Tennis</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Squash</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Padel</span></li>
</ul>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">But also:</span></p>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Weightlifting</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Painting</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Knitting</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Typing</span></li>
</ul>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">If you regularly play tennis or </span><a href="https://www.padelpadelpadel.com/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">padel</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, the risk of getting tennis elbow heightens as the repetitive movement and force you use during the sports affects your muscles. If your elbow feels tight, sore or it actually hurts, you can practice yoga by doing easy poses and stretching exercises to aid relief. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0195/9310/1376/files/pexels-photo-1103829_480x480.jpg?v=1627558090" alt="Padel tennis" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"></span></p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">Yoga to relieve tennis elbow</span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">An important thing to remember when practicing yoga if you have tennis elbow, is that you should never do poses that require you to bear your full weight onto your hands </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">with your wrists and elbows in extension. Besides the fact that this will most likely hurt, it also will not benefit your tennis elbow at all. By doing gentle exercises that won’t ask too much of your elbow, yoga can relieve pain caused by your tennis elbow and eventually even help it to disappear. But do remember, that with tennis elbow, rest is also super important!</span></p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">Yoga exercises for tennis elbow: 3 exercises that can help</span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">If you’re unfamiliar with yoga, it might be helpful to consult our </span><a href="https://www.yogi-bare.com/blogs/find-your-y-b/beginners-yoga-for-flexibility-guide" title="Beginners guide"><span style="font-weight: 400;">beginners guide to yoga</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. But don’t worry, because we have selected three simple yoga poses and exercises that will help your tennis elbow. Nothing too crazy or complicated. Be mindful not to hyperextend your elbow during upper-body exercises.</span></p>
<h3><span style="font-weight: 400;">1. Cobra stretch</span></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Lie down on your front, place your hands on your</span><a href="https://www.yogi-bare.co.uk/collections/yoga-mats/"><span style="font-weight: 400;"> yoga mat</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> and slowly press your upper body up, while keeping your hips and legs pressed into the ground. Avoid hyperextending your elbows or put too much weight on your hands. Hold this pose for a few seconds, as holding it for much longer won’t benefit your tennis elbow.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0195/9310/1376/files/180228_Speedo_RB_SHOT_45_09040_v1_480x480.jpg?v=1553686030" alt="Cobra stretch" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"></span></p>
<h3><span style="font-weight: 400;">2. Warrior pose</span></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Stand up straight and step out until your feet are three or four feet apart. Now, turn your right foot slightly to the right and your left foot 90 degrees to the left. Bring your arms up and keep them parallel to the floor. </span></p>
<h3><span style="font-weight: 400;">3. Extended triangle pose</span></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This extended triangle pose will help to stretch both elbows and wrists and reduce the pain caused by tennis elbow. From the warrior pose, keep standing with your feet apart measuring the width of your hip. Raise your left arm upwards and stretch it as far as comfortable. Bring your right hand to your right ankle and touch the ground with your fingertips. Hold this pose for one minute and repeat one the other side.</span></p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.yogi-bare.com/blogs/find-your-y-b/find-your-summer-flow</id>
    <published>2021-08-06T09:37:32-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-08-06T09:37:45-05:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.yogi-bare.com/blogs/find-your-y-b/find-your-summer-flow"/>
    <title>Find Your Summer Flow</title>
    <author>
      <name>James Oakley</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p><span>Summertime is a wonderful time for yoga. The sun’s shining, you can go out-doors and we all feel a bit more motivated to do something more productive with our day. That said, when the weather’s hot and muggy, exercise feels harder, not to mention the fact that we sweat more. </span></p>
<p><span>Early morning or late evening are the best times to practise yoga during summer and stay cool. It’s also vital to drink enough water to keep hydrated. Summer is a time for a change, so why not embrace the season and try out a new accessory this summer?</span></p>
<br>
<h2>What is a Yoga Towel? </h2>
<p><span>Yoga towels have been specifically designed for use with yoga. They’re made from a highly absorbent material with dense microfibres, more so than your average bath towel.</span></p>
<p><span>These highly effective towels wick away sweat and moisture, with the primary purpose of maintaining grip, to prevent you slipping and sliding around on your yoga mat. The good thing about them is that they don’t become soggy and wet, like a regular towel would, instead drying out very quickly. At the end of the session, you can pop them on a wash to keep them fresh and hygienic.</span></p>
<p><span>Most yoga towels are fitted to the size of a traditional yoga mat, and some have small grips underneath to keep them in place. This is a great investment if you’re prone to sweating a lot, practise hot yoga, want to stay comfortable during summertime, have to share mats at a yoga studio or for those times, when you feel like having some extra cushioning for your mat.</span></p>
<br>
<h2>What is a Yoga Wheel?</h2>
<p><span>Sitting hunched at a desk all-day or staring into screens 24/7 is having a hugely detrimental effect on our bodies. More than ever we’re suffering unbearable tension in our back and shoulders. </span></p>
<p><span>Fortunately, you don’t have to break the bank to visit an expensive spa to iron out those knots these days. Yoga wheels are a simple device, hollow and circular shaped, that help with deeper stretching, improving flexibility, supporting challenging poses, strengthening the core, and releasing muscle tension, especially in those hard-to-reach places.</span></p>
<br>
<h2>Summer Yoga Routine:</h2>
<br>
<h2><strong>Get Prepared</strong></h2>
<p><span>Apart from a </span><a href="https://www.yogi-bare.com/collections/yoga-wheels" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><b>Yogi Bare Yoga Wheel</b></a><span>, vital for increased flexibility and support, you’ll also need a non-slip mat for this routine. Bring a yoga towel if you like using one for extra comfort or think you’ll sweat more in the warmer weather too.</span></p>
<p><span>Staying indoors? W</span><span>e’d recommend our high performance </span><a href="https://www.yogi-bare.com/collections/original-paws" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><b>Yogi-Bare Paws Natural Rubber Extreme Grip Mat</b></a><span>. </span></p>
<p><span>For an invigorating outdoor summer yoga session, our portable </span><a href="https://www.yogi-bare.com/collections/yoga-mats/Teddy" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><b>Yogi-Bare Teddy Lightweight Travel Mat</b></a><span>, can be easily transported, then cleaned in a washing machine afterwards.</span></p>
<br>
<h2>5 Minute Yoga Wheel Work-out</h2>
<p><span>It’s great to incorporate a 5-minute yoga wheel work-out into your regular yoga routine or as a way of stretching after doing another form of exercise.</span></p>
<br>
<h2>Forward Fold</h2>
<p><span>Loosen shoulders and iron away those dastardly knots with this easy pose. </span></p>
<p><span>Get yourself into a seated position. The wheel should now be positioned under your calf muscles. Using your arms, reach forwards, placing your hands on the wheel to pull yourself deeper into the pose. Remain there as long as you like, inhaling and exhaling slowly and deeply. </span></p>
<br>
<h2>Child’s Pose</h2>
<p><span>Another lovely pose to open up the space between your shoulders and alleviate back-ache. As it’s a restful pose, you can use this one to recover in between more challenging asanas too. </span></p>
<p><span>Kneeling on the floor, bring yourself into child’s pose by touching your big toes together and sitting on your heels. On your next breath, bend forwards so that your torso is between your thighs. Head should be face down, with chin touching the floor, whilst arms reach forward, fingers touching floor.</span></p>
<p><span>To incorporate your yoga wheel into this pose, position your hands on either side of the wheel at the front of the mat. Keep your head down and gently roll the wheel forward, keeping your chest pressed to the floor. To get the full benefit, we’d suggest staying in this pose for a few minutes, enjoying the release of tension.</span></p>
<br>
<h2>Spinal Stretch</h2>
<p><span>There’s nothing like a spinal stretch for ultimate satisfaction. Another easy one, place your yoga wheel into the centre of your back and lie on top of it. Next bring your arms to the side and let your head hang back, feeling the soothing stretch.</span></p>
<br>
<h2>20-Minute Yoga Wheel Work-out</h2>
<p><span>Fancy a longer work-out? Why not follow this routine instead:</span></p>
<ul>
<li><span>Mountain Pose</span></li>
<li><span>Sun Salutations (at least a few rounds)</span></li>
<li><span>Warrior 1</span></li>
<li><span>Warrior 2</span></li>
<li><span>Extended Side Angle</span></li>
<li><span>Downward Facing Dog</span></li>
<li><span>Half-Moon Pose</span></li>
<li><span>Staff Pose</span></li>
<li><span>Forward Fold (with yoga wheel)</span></li>
<li><span>Child’s Pose (with yoga wheel)</span></li>
<li><span>Spinal Stretch (with yoga wheel)</span></li>
</ul>
<br>
<p><span>Now you can really go to town and add some more yoga wheel exercises in to finish off this strengthening routine. </span></p>
<p><span>If you suffer tight hamstrings, try using your wheel for the Half-Pyramid Pose. Start by getting into the traditional marriage proposal pose. Keeping your torso pulled upwards, roll the wheel under the thigh of your front leg, lifting your leg higher so that the back of your calf is resting on it. </span></p>
<p><span>Use your hands to ease the wheel forward to extend your front leg until the wheel is supporting your calf near to your ankle. On the next breath, flex your foot and lengthen your spine. Exhale and reach forward with your arms towards the wheel, whilst maintaining a straight spine.</span></p>
<p><span>Another simple but effective exercise for engaging the hip flexors and improving balance is to sit on your wheel with feet slightly apart. Keeping a steady, engaged core, lift one leg. Hold for 10 breaths then switch to the opposite foot.</span></p>
<br>
<p><span>If you’d like to add more yoga wheel exercises into your repertoire, read </span><a href="https://www.yogi-bare.com/blogs/find-your-y-b/5-ways-to-use-a-yoga-wheel-for-back-pain" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><b>5 Ways to Use a Yoga Wheel for Back Pain</b></a><span> for more ideas.</span></p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.yogi-bare.com/blogs/find-your-y-b/yoga-mats-for-all-levels</id>
    <published>2021-08-02T03:34:56-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-08-02T03:41:05-05:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.yogi-bare.com/blogs/find-your-y-b/yoga-mats-for-all-levels"/>
    <title>Yoga Mats For All Levels: Beginners to Professional</title>
    <author>
      <name>James Oakley</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p><span>Whether you’re a yoga newbie or a devoted yogi, the best yoga mat will aid your asanas and enhance your practise. A grippy yoga mat will also prevent slipping and sliding, improve your balance, support your joints, and most importantly, prevent injuries. </span></p>
<p><span>Originally founded by Kat, a yogi, teacher and student, Yogi Bare’s mission has always been to create high-performance, eco-sensitive yoga mats with a sense of fun and personality. Here’s our guide to finding the best one for your level and individual needs. </span></p>
<br>
<h2>Beginner’s Yoga Mat</h2>
<p><span>It’s the original. It’s a classic. A supremely comfy yoga mat, the </span><a href="https://www.yogi-bare.com/collections/original-paws" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><b>Yogi Bare Paws Natural Rubber Mat</b></a><span> offers the grip of your life and is ideal for those starting out. Choose between red, blue, green, black, or grey. </span></p>
<p><span>Made from natural, biodegradable, sustainable rubber, our mats are free from harmful chemical residues. Even the stylish etching is laser engraved to avoid the use of anything toxic. The rubber is sourced from a sustainable forest and if you purchase our extra-special</span><span> </span><a href="https://www.yogi-bare.com/products/yogi-bare-plant-a-tree-mat" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><b>Wild Paws</b></a><span> </span>design<span>, a tree is planted in return.</span></p>
<br>
<h2>Professional Yoga Mat</h2>
<p><span>As your practise advances, you’ll probably move onto more challenging asanas and try out different yoga disciplines. And you may also want to find a mat that captures the spiritual aspect of yoga and helps you feel grounded.</span></p>
<p><span>Our </span><a href="https://www.yogi-bare.com/products/flow-paws-natural-rubber-extreme-grip-yoga-mat" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><b>Paws Flow Mat</b></a><span> is longer and wider than most other yoga mats. Dimensions are 180cm x 66cm. The additional length and width ensure that you have the extra space to move around, ideal for taking on those more difficult poses. With </span><span>a smooth anti-slip top, it provides the signature Yogi Bare expert grip. All of our Paws mats are thick yoga mats with a 4mm thickness, to support the impact on ankles, wrists, and knees.</span></p>
<p><span>The stunning imprinted photograph of the ocean subconsciously encourages your flow, in the same way as water flows effortlessly and infinitely. The design is awe-inspiring, whilst simultaneously conveying a sense of perspective.</span></p>
<br>
<h2>Travel Yoga Mat</h2>
<p><span>Our </span><a href="https://www.yogi-bare.com/collections/yoga-mats/Teddy" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><b>Teddy Mat</b></a><span> is great for taking on holiday, practising yoga outdoors, hot yoga or to bring with you to a yoga class if you prefer to use your own. </span></p>
<p><span>A perfectly portable, lightweight, high-performance non-slip yoga mat with superb grip. It can be used on any surface including the floor, grass, or sand. The really cool thing is that it’s foldable into a small square so you can easily pack it into a bag or suitcase, and it only weighs 1.5kg too. </span></p>
<p><span>Not only that, but this travel yoga mat incorporates a velvet microfiber surface that becomes extremely grippy under sweat and moisture. Meanwhile, the strong natural sustainable rubber base grips hard to the floor, preventing bunching up. So, staycation or vacation, make sure it’s on your packing list.</span></p>
<br><br>
<h2>Wide Yoga Mat</h2>
<p><span>If you’re looking for something longer and wider than normal with more room to play, we recommend our </span><a href="https://www.yogi-bare.com/products/yogi-bare-paws-x-yoga-mat" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><b>Yogi-Bare Paws X Mat.</b></a><span> Like our Paws Flow Mat, it’s dimensions are </span><span>180cm x 66cm.</span><span> </span></p>
<p><span>This is just the job for Acroyoga when there’s two of you, for more advanced poses, or a faster-paced yoga session when you need to move around more. Of course, it goes without saying that this mat utilises advanced grip technology to prevent you falling out of pose.</span></p>
<br>
<h2>How Do I Keep My Yoga Mat Clean?</h2>
<p><span>Now that you’ve chosen your yoga mat, you’ll want to keep it looking pristine. Be aware that sweat, dirt and grime can build up on your yoga mat, so remember to give it some TLC to keep it in optimum condition. Fortunately, natural rubber is unbelievably easy to clean. Our </span><a href="https://www.yogi-bare.com/collections/original-paws" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><b>Paws</b></a><b>,<span> </span></b><a href="https://www.yogi-bare.com/products/yogi-bare-paws-x-yoga-mat" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><b>Paws X</b></a><span> and </span><a href="https://www.yogi-bare.com/products/yogi-bare-plant-a-tree-mat" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><b>Wild Paws</b></a><span> mats can be cleaned once weekly by wiping down both sides with warm water diluted with completely natural fresh lemon juice. </span></p>
<p><span>Our highly transportable </span><a href="https://www.yogi-bare.com/collections/yoga-mats/Teddy" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><b>Teddy Mat</b></a><span> </span><span>is also ultra-convenient and easy to maintain too. Pop your mat on a quick wash in your washing machine at 30/40 degrees with a small amount of detergent. To dry, hang it up and store it out of direct sunlight. </span></p>
<br>
<p><span>If you liked this blog, try reading</span><span> </span><a href="https://www.yogi-bare.com/blogs/find-your-y-b/what-should-you-wear-to-a-yoga-class" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><b>What Should You Wear to a Yoga Class</b></a></p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.yogi-bare.com/blogs/find-your-y-b/what-should-you-wear-to-a-yoga-class</id>
    <published>2021-07-28T09:20:43-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-28T09:20:55-05:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.yogi-bare.com/blogs/find-your-y-b/what-should-you-wear-to-a-yoga-class"/>
    <title>What Should You Wear To A Yoga Class?</title>
    <author>
      <name>James Oakley</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p><span>Starting a new class in any discipline can be nerve-wracking, without the added stress of what to wear. Social media platforms don’t exactly help because let’s be honest, the pictures of stick-thin women parading around in designer yoga wear isn’t the reality of most classes. In fact, you’ll find people of all shapes and sizes at a yoga class and guess what? They’re all wearing different outfits too. So there’s no set rule about what to wear, except that it should help you feel relaxed throughout the class. Clothes should be about comfort, rather than style and you certainly don’t need to spend vast amounts of money on a new wardrobe!</span></p>
<p><span> </span></p>
<h2>What to Wear to a Yoga Class</h2>
<p><span>Yoga requires a lot of bending and stretching so you need clothes that allow free movement. Equally, you don’t want anything too loose that will bunch up, cover your face, expose your tummy, or get in the way. Clothing that rides up, can also be rather distracting and block your vision. Wearing something that stays put is best when it comes to yoga.</span></p>
<p><span>It’s also highly likely that you’re going to sweat, so go for light and breathable fabrics. This is where activewear or yoga wear can have an advantage as it’s specifically made with this in mind. This is especially true for Bikram (Hot) Yoga, where clothes that wick away moisture are a great idea.</span></p>
<p><span> </span></p>
<h2>Do You Need Yoga Pants?</h2>
<p><span>The quick answer is no. All you need is something comfortable that facilitates movement. Many people opt for regular leggings, so you don't necessarily have to buy a pair of branded yoga pants. </span></p>
<p><span>In fact, the original yoga pants were leggings made especially for yoga. Since then, leggings have become the daily outfit for many so there’s not that much distinction between leggings and yoga pants nowadays, except the branding and pricing. </span></p>
<p><span>That said, some yoga pants can be exceptional quality and are made from material that’s highly breathable and sweat absorbing. If you want to splash the cash, why not, there’s nothing wrong with being fashionable, just bear in mind that a regular pair of leggings, especially when you’re starting out, can be just as fit for purpose. Either way, both are wonderfully comfortable, fit the body snugly and are usually made of stretchy material that let you bend easily and stretch whilst in pose.</span></p>
<p><span>If you’re doing hot yoga, you might find yoga pants or leggings too much, so try a fitted pair of yoga shorts instead.</span></p>
<p><span> </span></p>
<h2>Do You Need Long Sleeves or Short Sleeves for Yoga?</h2>
<p><span>If you’re happy to expose some flesh, a form-fitting singlet or tank (work-out vest) can be a great option. Because these tops don’t have sleeves, they allow unrestricted arm movement, fit really well, and stay in place throughout all poses and postures.</span></p>
<p><span>A slightly tighter fitting longer-sleeved top can also work so that sleeves don’t ride up when you’re reaching upwards or outwards. If you’re not an extrovert who’s keen on flaunting cleavage, make sure you have a high-necked top to avoid that problem. Another good idea is to pair a long-sleeved top with a singlet, especially if you want to de-layer as you warm up during the session. Wearing a singlet underneath also means that if your top does fall out of place, you’ll retain your modesty too.</span></p>
<p><span>As with any exercise, wear a well-fitting bra or even a sports bra for extra support, particularly if you’re big-busted. We especially love </span><a href="https://scentered.me/collections/coppafeel/coppafeel?sort_by=manual" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><b>Coppafeel! Scentered Sports Bra</b></a><span> which can be worn as a sports bra or a workout vest.</span></p>
<p><span> </span></p>
<h2>Do You Need Shoes for Yoga?</h2>
<p><span>No! Yoga is done without shoes. Feet are extremely important in yoga because the contact that they have with the floor provides stability for balancing and grounding of the self. Going barefoot means that your feet and toes, usually constrained within a shoe, have the rare chance to fully extend and stretch too. </span></p>
<p><span>Certain yoga poses do require you to rest your hands on the floor, so it’s not good etiquette to walk across a yoga studio. (Take them off before you enter the studio). Having your own yoga mat provides extra grip for your feet, reduces the risks of injuries, and provides support for your joints. Not to mention that you don’t have to use floorspace that’s been walked on by other people. Try a</span><span> </span><a href="https://www.yogi-bare.com/collections/original-paws" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><b>Yogi Bare Paws Natural Rubber Mat</b></a><span> for extreme grip.</span></p>
<p><span>Lastly, shoes would simply get in the way, make you less nimble, cause you to over-balance and there’s always the potential to ruin your yoga mat or step on someone’s toes. Ouch! </span></p>
<p><span> </span></p>
<h2>Do You Need Socks for Yoga?</h2>
<p><span>It can be tempting to wear socks to a yoga class. Let’s face it, feet can smell, get cold and many of us are embarrassed about how they look. Ultimately, there’s no rule to say that you can’t wear socks.</span></p>
<p><span>The problem is that socks interfere with our connection with the ground, making it harder to balance. They can also be slippery so there’s more chance of an accident or injury. If you feel that you must wear socks for your own preference or for hygienic reasons, opt for socks that have been designed for exercise that have a grippier sole.</span></p>
<p><span>So, now you’re fully set with what to wear, it’s time to quit the faffing and do some yoga!</span></p>
<p><span> </span></p>
<p>If you liked this article, try reading <a href="https://www.yogi-bare.com/blogs/find-your-y-b/our-top-5-favourite-sustainable-wellness-brands" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><strong>Our</strong> <b>Top 5 Favourite Sustainable Wellness Brands</b></a></p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.yogi-bare.com/blogs/find-your-y-b/7-mental-health-benefits-of-meditation-and-yoga</id>
    <published>2021-07-27T04:20:53-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-27T04:21:04-05:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.yogi-bare.com/blogs/find-your-y-b/7-mental-health-benefits-of-meditation-and-yoga"/>
    <title>7 Mental Health Benefits Of Meditation And Yoga</title>
    <author>
      <name>James Oakley</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The ancient discipline of yoga incorporates poses to stretch and flex the muscles, deeper, diaphragmatic breathing, and meditation. All of which build strength, clarity, awareness and harmony between mind and body. It’s obvious that yoga provides many physical benefits like flexibility, core strength and cardio, and circulatory health.</span><span> </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">But now, more than ever, we’re concerned about our mental health too. Self-care is the latest buzzword and with more and more of us addicted to social media, the ongoing global pandemic and life lived at a ridiculously fast pace nowadays, many of us are looking inwards at our own inner mental health. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"> </span></p>
<h2>Yoga and Mental Health</h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">With millions around the world taking up yoga, there’s been a plethora of research around it confirming what we already knew! Regular yoga practice has numerous mental health benefits. These include: </span></p>
<ol>
<li>
<span style="font-weight: 400;"></span><span style="font-weight: 400;">   <span> </span></span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Fights depression</span>
</li>
<li>
<span style="font-weight: 400;"></span><span style="font-weight: 400;">   <span> </span></span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Promotes better sleep</span>
</li>
<li>
<span style="font-weight: 400;"></span><span style="font-weight: 400;">   <span> </span></span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Relieves anxiety</span>
</li>
<li>
<span style="font-weight: 400;"></span><span style="font-weight: 400;">   <span> </span></span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Combats fatigue</span>
</li>
<li>
<span style="font-weight: 400;"></span><span style="font-weight: 400;">   <span> </span></span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Decreases stress</span>
</li>
<li>
<span style="font-weight: 400;"></span><span style="font-weight: 400;">   <span> </span></span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Improves focus</span>
</li>
<li>
<span style="font-weight: 400;"></span><span style="font-weight: 400;">   <span> </span></span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Improves tolerance to pain</span>
</li>
</ol>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">It’s a pretty impressive tick-list, isn’t it? There’s no doubt that yoga can enhance your experience of daily life. Of course, life gets in the way sometimes, but that said, yoga is the perfect form of exercise. It can be done anywhere, any-time, alone or with others and aside from a yoga mat, there’s not much else you need to get going. Incidentally, we love the<span> </span></span><a href="https://www.yogi-bare.co.uk/collections/yoga-mats/Teddy" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><b>Yogi Bare Teddy Non-Slip Yoga Mat</b></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, perfectly portable with superb grip. Get one of these and you can get your fix of yoga anytime you want!</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"> </span></p>
<h2>Mental Health and Meditation</h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Many yoga devotees practise regular meditation alongside their yoga and it’s a lovely way to finish your yoga routine.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">It’s always been believed that meditation has extensive neurological benefits and finally, it's being backed by science too. The results of recent research have been truly outstanding because regular mindfulness meditation actually makes changes to the brain, increasing grey matter that handles memories, learning and emotional regulation. Other studies have also proven that it increases focus and concentration and lowers levels of cortisol, the stress hormone. All of which enhance our mental health, lifestyle, quality of sleep and of course have knock-on positive effects for our physical health too.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"> </span></p>
<h2>Can Yoga Help Anxiety, Depression and Stress</h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Stress, anxiety, and depression are often inter-linked, and it can be difficult to discern where one stops, and another begins. They can manifest in so many ways too and each person’s experience of mental illness is unique. It can reveal itself through physical sickness, having a tight chest, experiencing emotional outbursts, suffering low mood, as well as poor sleep, physical aches and pains and unhealthy coping strategies like eating disorders or alcohol abuse. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">On the other hand, yoga and meditation promote relaxation, the polar opposite to anxiety, stress, and depression. They build on your ability to stay centred, calm, and focused, strategies that are vital for stress management. By simply taking a pause to breathe, meditate, or stretch,  the mind is cleared and instantly re-directed away from the source or trigger. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Yogic breathing is so much deeper and controlled. Ultimately that means that more oxygen is inhaled and gets to your organs. So your body can relax it's fight or flight mechanism and decrease the amount of cortisol it's releasing because there’s no threat to receiving oxygen, its lifeblood.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">So, next time you start to experience anxiety or feel stressed, try holding your arms up, then go into a side bend. Take a deep inhalation as you bend into the pose, hold it, then breathe out as you come up. Just by doing this seemingly innocuous pose, the relaxation process will be kickstarted. Cortisol in your system decreases and guess what? You feel more relaxed and less stressed. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Yoga and meditation also give you a greater awareness of what’s happening to your body so it’s easier to spot the early signs of a mental health issue. They keep you in the moment which is great because so many mental health issues are around what may happen in the future. Learning to be present is a great tool for managing mental health.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">And because yoga is exercise, it’s a natural way to get serotonin, ‘the happy hormone’, flowing. It’s thought that this hormone is a major factor of depression and those that suffer from it, often have lower levels. Exercising makes you feel happier and more positive, couple that with focusing on the present and feeling relaxed and you can see why many are viewing yoga as an effective therapy for depression. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"> </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">If you enjoyed reading this article, try<span> </span></span><a href="https://www.yogi-bare.com/blogs/find-your-y-b/5-things-improving-your-flexibility-can-do-for-your-mental-health" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><b>‘5 Things Improving Your Flexibility can do for your Mental Health’</b></a><span> </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">or<span> </span></span><a href="https://www.yogi-bare.com/blogs/find-your-y-b/10-grounding-activities-to-release-stress" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><b>’10 Grounding Activities to Release Stress’</b></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.yogi-bare.com/blogs/find-your-y-b/how-yoga-can-help-improve-athletic-performance</id>
    <published>2021-07-23T14:26:39-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-23T14:27:15-05:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.yogi-bare.com/blogs/find-your-y-b/how-yoga-can-help-improve-athletic-performance"/>
    <title>How Yoga Can Help Improve Athletic Performance</title>
    <author>
      <name>James Oakley</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p><span>With the commencement of the Tokyo Olympics, there’s bound to be a significant surge in people becoming interested in fitness. After all, there’s nothing like watching an elite athlete winning at their sport to make us want to get off our sofa and into the Lycra. Well, okay, not all of us exactly. But if you’re feeling in any way inspired by the games, of course you could head to the gym, swimming pool or athletic track. Even so, did you ever consider that you could just as easily head to the yoga studio? That’s because yoga can seriously help to improve athletic performance and here’s how!</span></p>
<p><span> </span></p>
<h2>Yoga for Runners</h2>
<p><span>Endurance is something that many runners struggle with, especially when it comes to cross-country or long-distances. Holding poses can really challenge your stamina and endurance. On the note of physicality, yoga also helps to increase core strength. A healthy core ensures that the back and body is strong and healthy too. Yoga also stabilizes the muscles that are missed by other workouts, the muscles that are there to protect our joints and spine. This is especially important for the legs, glutes and lower back muscles which are often most impacted by running.</span></p>
<p><span>Yoga also supports the body’s recovery whether it be post-run, workout, or injury. That’s because it helps the body to cool down, elongates and stretches muscles, promotes flexibility, and releases lactic acid, aiding muscle recovery, repair, and blood circulation to the muscles. In turn, this decreases soreness, muscle tension and helps by preventing injuries. </span></p>
<p><span>Improving athleticism isn’t just about physical fitness though. Mental aptitude is the key to an athlete’s mindset and focus is something that yoga can build upon. Yoga devotees report that holding poses helps them to tune out other distractions, which is why meditation and yoga often go hand in hand. </span></p>
<p><b> </b></p>
<h2>Yoga for Cyclists</h2>
<p><span>Cyclists also experience many of the same benefits from yoga as runners do. Something else that’s really helpful to cyclists is that yoga aids balance and posture. Think of all those hair-raisingly sharp corners on The Tour De France. It’s vital to be able maintain your balance and bend easily, to prevent accidents, falls or injuries, whether that be at race level or even just whilst you’re out for a pleasurable cycle ride on country roads.</span></p>
<p><span>A cyclist’s posture can be affected because of the time spent hunched over the handlebars. When you do this, it contracts your muscles, leading to muscle tension. Yoga works to counteract these contracted muscle groups by elongating them, especially the long-suffering spine. Legs, glutes, back, arms and shoulders can all suffer a build-up of lactic acid during a fast-paced or long cycle ride, which can be released by a tailored yoga routine.</span></p>
<p><span> </span></p>
<h2>Yoga for Swimmers</h2>
<p><span>Stamina and functional strength are crucial for swimmers. Guess what? In most sports, this is achieved with traditional resistance training and protein shakes. Yoga needs neither, instead it forces your body to hold its body weight in various positions, initiating the stabilising and core muscles and promoting endurance.</span></p>
<p><span>There’s also a lot of repetitive action because swimming strokes repeatedly use the same muscle groups. This can lead to muscle fatigue, tightness, soreness, and limited motion especially when muscles are not stretched adequately enough. All too often, other muscles can overcompensate, leading to injury and tension in the surrounding muscles too. A post-workout yoga session to stretch out the muscles is the perfect tonic to a demanding swim!</span></p>
<p><b> </b></p>
<h2>Yoga for Calisthenics</h2>
<p><span>Yoga and calisthenics are similar in the sense that they use large groups of muscles at the same time. Both improve posture, strength, stability, and body composition. The great thing is that you can make a yoga routine way more interesting by combining it with calisthenics and vice versa.</span></p>
<p><span>A great way to mix it up is to incorporate calisthenics exercises at the start of a routine for a warm-up and cardio workout. Then, to slow the pace, cool down and facilitate post work-out stretching, you can move into a yoga routine. It’s the perfect, synergistic partnership for all round fitness, flexibility, and stamina.</span></p>
<p><span> </span></p>
<h2>What Equipment Do I Need for Yoga?</h2>
<p><span>Hardly anything at all! The good news is that there’s no expensive equipment or gimmicks needed to get going with yoga.</span></p>
<p><span>The only thing you should invest in is a non-slip yoga mat, to prevent slipping and sliding, support your joints and prevent any accidents or injuries. Luckily, you’ve come to the right place. We’d recommend getting your hands on the </span><a href="https://www.yogi-bare.co.uk/collections/yoga-mats/Paws" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><b>Yogi Bare Paws Natural Rubber Mat</b></a><span> for extreme grip. One you’ve had one of these, you’ll never look back. And who knows where you’ll end up. Word is that Brisbane’s just been selected for the 2032 Olympic Games…..</span></p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.yogi-bare.com/blogs/find-your-y-b/the-history-of-acupressure</id>
    <published>2021-07-20T10:09:05-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-20T10:09:16-05:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.yogi-bare.com/blogs/find-your-y-b/the-history-of-acupressure"/>
    <title>The History Of Acupressure</title>
    <author>
      <name>James Oakley</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p><span>If you’ve ever had a massage or spa treatment, it’s very likely that you’ve experienced acupressure in some form or another. While it originated in China thousands of years ago, fast forward to 2021 and there’s never been a better time for millennials to incorporate acupressure into modern life. With precious little time for self-care and way too much time staring at screens, acupressure can be just the tonic to relax, re-energise and release muscle tension.</span></p>
<p> </p>
<h2>A Brief History of Acupressure</h2>
<p><span>Acupuncture and acupressure are closely related, and it’s thought that these therapies originate in China dating as far back as 2000 B.C. Over time, these practises spread across the world and different disciplines developed. Shiatsu, the Japanese version developed to use palm pressure, stretching, kneading and other manipulation along with the finger and thumb pressure. Reflexology, another form of acupressure concentrated on the application of pressure to the sole of the foot.</span></p>
<p><span>During the 1960s and 1970s, acupressure began to gain momentum across Europe and America with several Hollywood celebrities dabbling in the practise. Today, whilst it still remains hugely popular across Asia, there are also thousands of acupressure practitioners across the western world. Even the practise of Yoga has embraced acupressure with Acu-Yoga, which focuses on certain yoga poses that place pressure on acupoints.</span></p>
<p> </p>
<h2>What is Acupressure?</h2>
<p><span>Acupuncture without needles is a common description for this branch of Chinese medicine. Essentially pressure is applied to specific points on the skin known as acupoints.</span></p>
<p><span>It works on the philosophy that a life-force or energy (known as Chi) is constantly flowing along the body through pathways (Meridians). When these pathways become blocked or there’s an imbalance, it’s believed that there’s a knock-on effect which can result in fatigue or illness. So, an acupressure practitioner will apply pressure along the relevant meridians to restore the balance.</span></p>
<p> </p>
<h2>How Does Acupressure Work?</h2>
<p><span>Having an acupressure treatment is quite different to a traditional massage. It’s usually done through clothes without oils. A practitioner will apply pressure to stimulate various acupoints around the body. They mostly do this with their fingers and thumbs but may also use their feet and knees.</span></p>
<p><span>The acupoints tend to be at the nerve endings of meridians so are easily stimulated and tension in the muscle fibres is released in the corresponding muscle. As a result, energy blockages within meridians are cleared but it's also believed that its effects are more far-reaching and that endorphins that give us an emotional high and relieve pain are also released.</span></p>
<p><span>Acupressure is regularly used by Chinese people to manage common ailments, promote wellbeing, and boost the immune system. Over in the west, we’re finally realising just how beneficial acupressure can be and how it can enhance our hectic, and often unhealthy lifestyles.</span></p>
<p> </p>
<h2>How Can Acupressure Help Me?</h2>
<p><span>Life these days really is nonstop and it’s important to factor in time for self-care. Couple that with sitting at a desk all day or staring at screens and it’s not surprising that the incidence of headaches, migraines, neck strain, backache, lethargy, poor sleep, and stress have all increased.</span></p>
<p><span>The simple technique of acupressure is so quick and accessible and can be used to counteract these common complaints. Research into acupressure has shown that it can help to promote relaxation, improve sleep, and increase energy, as well as ease muscle tension, manage pain, and lessen stress and anxiety. </span></p>
<p> </p>
<h2>Acupressure at Home</h2>
<p><span>Imagine being able to have acupressure at home anytime you’d like? Well now you can with the Yogi Bare acupressure range of products. With</span><span> 210 pressure points on our acupressure mat, the painless round plastic spikes create gentle stimulation, applying pressure to the body where acupuncture would normally apply a needle.</span></p>
<p><span>Create a relaxing ritual by using the </span><a href="https://www.yogi-bare.com/collections/acupressure/Acupressure-Pillow" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><b>Yogi Bare Acupressure Pillow</b></a><a href="https://www.yogi-bare.co.uk/products/yogi-bare-acupressure-pillow-grey-pillow-of-nails-for-tension-relief-and-deep-relaxation"><span>,</span></a><span> alongside a </span><a href="https://www.yogi-bare.com/collections/acupressure/Acupressure-mat" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><b>Yogi Bare Acupressure Mat</b></a><span> 20-40 minutes several times a week. </span><span>We’d recommend experimenting with the position of your acupressure pillow which should be arranged under the neck crevice and feel comfortable. You might also want to try positioning your legs up against a wall for extra support.</span></p>
<span>Why not put on some relaxing music or listen to a meditation? We love a </span><a href="https://scentered.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><b>Scentered Aromatherapy Candle</b></a><span> to create the perfect ambiance or if that’s not your thing, try popping on a lavender eye pillow and feel yourself drift away. </span><span>When you’ve finished, don’t forget to rehydrate with some water as acupressure kickstarts the detoxifying process, so toxins will need to be flushed out.</span>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.yogi-bare.com/blogs/find-your-y-b/yoga-accessories-to-boost-your-yoga-abilities</id>
    <published>2021-07-16T09:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-16T09:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.yogi-bare.com/blogs/find-your-y-b/yoga-accessories-to-boost-your-yoga-abilities"/>
    <title>Yoga Accessories To Boost Your Yoga Abilities</title>
    <author>
      <name>James Oakley</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">When you’re new to yoga, a yoga mat might be the only yoga attribute you know of. So you must be happy to hear that there are many yoga accessories that you can use to boost your practice. Whether you use it for extra comfort, flexibility or a deepened stretch, yoga accessories are great to use during your yoga practice. To get you fully ready for your next yoga practice, we’re going to run you through the different yoga accessories, their benefits and how they can boost your yoga abilities.</span></p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">Yoga blocks for extra support and length </span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">As a yoga beginner, you might notice that some stretches are more difficult than others because you might not be as flexible yet. If this is the case, a </span><a href="https://www.yogi-bare.com/collections/props-blocks-straps/Block" title="Yoga block"><span style="font-weight: 400;">yoga block</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> will come in handy to provide you extra support and length. Your poses might be a bit wobbly and a yoga block can help you to stabilise your position and feel more comfortable on your yoga mat. Slowly improve your flexibility by using a yoga block. When stretching, place it under your feet or hands to make a stretch less intense. Once you improve your flexibility, you can slowly move the yoga block further away and eventually remove it entirely. An absolute essential for yoga beginners!</span></p>
<div style="text-align: left;"><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0195/9310/1376/products/Untitleddesign_6_480x480.jpg?v=1621268488" alt="Yoga block" style="margin-right: 112px; margin-left: 112px; float: none;"></div>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">Yoga mat carry straps</span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Next on the list are </span><a href="https://www.yogi-bare.com/collections/props-blocks-straps/Carry-strap" title="Yoga mat carry straps"><span style="font-weight: 400;">yoga mat carry straps</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, which come in handy when you have to take along your yoga mat often. Carrying a yoga mat can be uncomfortable, especially if you have to take the train or have to bike to your yoga practice. The mat unrolls quickly or you lose your grip. A yoga mat carry strap is the perfect solution as it allows you to transport your yoga mat without it rolling out. And even better: you can carry your yoga mat around your shoulder! That makes life a lot easier. </span></p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">Improve your flexibility and posture with a yoga wheel</span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Beginner yogi’s often struggle with flexibility and posture, which can lead to serious injuries if you’re not being careful enough. By using a </span><a href="https://www.yogi-bare.com/collections/props-blocks-straps/Wheel" title="Yoga wheel"><span style="font-weight: 400;">yoga wheel</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, you can deepen the stretches in the front of your body, so your shoulders, chest, abs and hip flexors. Besides that, it helps to improve posture, spine health and mobility which will gradually improve your yoga practice as well. Yoga wheels can also be used to strengthen your core or </span><a href="https://www.yogi-bare.com/blogs/find-your-y-b/do-yoga-wheels-help-back-pain" title="Yoga wheels back pain"><span style="font-weight: 400;">aid back pain</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. The possibilities of using a yoga wheel during your practice are endless!</span></p>
<div style="text-align: left;"><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0195/9310/1376/products/30_480x480.jpg?v=1623141289" alt="Yoga wheel" style="margin-right: 112px; margin-left: 112px; float: none;"></div>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">Travel yoga mats</span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">If you’re a traveler in heart and soul (in times when there’s no pandemic), taking your yoga mat with you can be very impractical. Especially if you travel light or are a backpacker, there’s simply no room for a yoga mat. Luckily, we have developed yoga mat that are particularly handy when you travel often. Our </span><a href="https://www.yogi-bare.com/collections/yoga-mats/Best-for_Travel" title="Travel yoga mats"><span style="font-weight: 400;">travel yoga mats</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> are lightweight, foldable, machine washable and most importantly: very very pretty. Our </span><a href="https://www.yogi-bare.com/products/yogi-bare-teddy-yoga-mat-luxury-velvet-feel-sweat-adaptive-mat" title="Teddy yoga mat"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Teddy yoga mat</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> has a tropical print on it, which immediately makes you feel like you’re far away from home - even if you’re stuck at home like we are now.</span></p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">Stretch straps  </span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Last but not least, </span><a href="https://www.yogi-bare.com/collections/props-blocks-straps/Strap" title="Yoga stretch strap"><span style="font-weight: 400;">yoga stretch straps</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> are a vital tool for any yogi, from beginners to advanced yoga practitioners. The strap enables you to ease into the more difficult postures, gradually opening your body up to achieving depth, endurance and mobility. Available in a cool space print, tropical print or a sophisticated black, the stretch straps can match your yoga mats perfectly. That way, you can enjoy the health benefits of your yoga practice and have a great aesthetic in the meantime as well!</span></p>
<div style="text-align: left;"><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0195/9310/1376/products/14_480x480.png?v=1623141079" alt="Stretch strap" style="margin-right: 112px; margin-left: 112px; float: none;"></div>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.yogi-bare.com/blogs/find-your-y-b/3-yoga-positions-perfect-for-a-non-slip-yoga-mat</id>
    <published>2021-07-15T10:08:36-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-15T10:12:11-05:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.yogi-bare.com/blogs/find-your-y-b/3-yoga-positions-perfect-for-a-non-slip-yoga-mat"/>
    <title>3 Yoga Positions Perfect For A Non Slip Yoga Mat</title>
    <author>
      <name>James Oakley</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<meta charset="UTF-8">
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Having a yoga mat that slips and slides across the floor can really hold you back from achieving your yoga goals. Here at Yogi Bare, we understand this, and have designed a range of ultra grippy yoga mats so you can spend more time perfecting your poses, and less time worrying about sliding off your mat!</span></p>
<br>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">Which Yoga Mat Has The Best Grip?</span></h2>
<br>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The </span><a href="https://www.yogi-bare.co.uk/collections/yoga-mats/Best-for_Ultra-Grip"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Extreme Grip Yoga Mat Collection</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> from Yogi Bare consists of 7 super sturdy yoga mats to keep you grounded throughout your workout. All of these mats are made from sustainably sourced natural rubber, we pride ourselves on creating the ultimate yoga mats, using only environmentally friendly materials, so you can practise yoga in style, whilst also protecting the planet. </span></p>
<br>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">For even more support you could try the </span><a href="https://www.yogi-bare.co.uk/products/yogi-bare-paws-x-yoga-mat"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Enhanced Grip Longer And Wider Yoga Mat</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. This mat has been designed with added length and width so you can feel confident and secure, there’s no slipping and sliding on this mat!</span></p>
<p> </p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/2128/0363/files/paws-x_480x480.jpg?v=1622617076" alt="Extreme Grip Yogi Bare Yoga Mat" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"></span></p>
<br>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">Which Yoga Positions Are Best For Non-Slip Yoga Mats?</span></h2>
<br>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">When buying a non-slip yoga mat you are also buying the reassurance that you’ll be able to master yoga poses that require balance.</span></p>
<br>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Balancing poses often rely on a non-slip yoga mat to keep you firm on the ground. Here are our top 3 balancing yoga poses for you to try!</span></p>
<br>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">#1 Tree Pose</span></h2>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Press your right foot into the ground.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Rise onto the tiptoes of your left foot. Transfer your weight from both feet to just one foot.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Bring your left knee up and hold it with both hands.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">With your left hand, pull your knee outwards. Your foot should rest either above or below the knee joint.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Rest your foot on the inside of your thigh. Push your thigh against the heel. It’ll feel like two forces pushing against each other, giving your hips a great stretch.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Keep your hips pointing forward. Only your knee should point to the side.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Position your hands into the prayer pose and relax your shoulders. </span></li>
</ul>
<br>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">#2 Downward Facing Dog</span></h2>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Start on all fours on the floor.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Push gently onto your toes as you lift your hips and straighten your knees. If this is challenging, keep a slight bend at your knees.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Keep your hips back, stretching out your back. If you want to increase the stretch, you can move your hands forwards.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Push down onto your palms and keep your leg muscles engaged while holding this pose.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Take a few deep breaths in this position before coming back down to all fours to release the pose.</span></li>
</ul>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;"></span></h2>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">#3 Warrior 2</span></h2>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Stretch arms out to the side, gently widen your stance.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Turn hip bones towards the side of your mat.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Your front knee needs to be over your front ankle whilst your back leg remains straight. Keep reaching outwards with both fingertips.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Your shoulders should align over your hips.</span></li>
</ul>
<p> </p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">There you have it, 3 poses to help improve your balance and core strength, made possible with non-slip yoga mats to keep you stable. Give them a go, once you’ve used a non-slip yoga mat you’ll never want to go back!</span></p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.yogi-bare.com/blogs/find-your-y-b/beginners-guide-to-hatha-yoga</id>
    <published>2021-07-07T03:49:11-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-07T03:50:11-05:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.yogi-bare.com/blogs/find-your-y-b/beginners-guide-to-hatha-yoga"/>
    <title>Beginners Guide To Hatha Yoga</title>
    <author>
      <name>James Oakley</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Even though hatha yoga might not immediately ring a bell, chances are high you have experienced it before if you’re into yoga. Hatha yoga has been around for centuries but has increased in popularity the past decades. To give you an easy introduction to the world of hatha yoga, we have created a beginners guide where you will find everything you need to know about hatha yoga. Or at least, it should be enough to get you started! </span></p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">What is hatha yoga?</span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The word ‘hatha’ means ‘force’ which makes hatha yoga ‘the yoga of force’. Hatha yoga is the type of yoga that typically comes to mind when you think about yoga. Hatha yoga involves breath, body and mind and is performed in classes by doing breathing exercises, yoga poses, and meditation. When booking a yoga class that is described as ‘hatha’, the class will typically involve a set of physical yoga poses and breathing exercises. With hatha yoga, these are practiced more slowly and with more static posture holds. </span></p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">Benefits of hatha yoga</span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Hatha yoga can be practiced for many different reasons and has proven to be beneficial in many different areas. The benefits of hatha yoga include stress relief, healthy habit support, improvement of emotional health and reducing back and arthritis pain. Besides that, hatha yoga can also help you to sleep better, strengthen your core muscles and improve depression symptoms. Overall, that seems like quite a long list of benefits! Reason enough to get started and book your first hatha yoga class. </span></p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">Hatha yoga poses</span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Speaking of hatha yoga classes, what can you expect from your first session? We’ll run you through a couple of popular hatha yoga poses to prepare you for your class. Let’s introduce you to our five favorite easy hatha yoga poses. </span></p>
<h3><span style="font-weight: 400;">1. Mountain pose</span></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This yoga might be the easiest to perform and even though it’s not a challenging pose, it will give your core muscles a good stretch. Simply stand straight, raise your hands above your head and press upward. Make sure your muscles are contracted to get a full body stretch.</span></p>
<h3><span style="font-weight: 400;">2. Tree pose</span></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">A famous yoga pose! From the mountain pose, place one foot against your knee, moving the other knee outwards. This one takes a bit of balance, but try to find your center of gravity and hold the position. If you want to, you can place your hands against each other either in front of your chest or above your head.</span></p>
<h3><span style="font-weight: 400;">3. Standing forward bend</span></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">From the tree pose, place your feet on the ground again and slowly move your upper body down while keeping your legs as straight as possible. You will feel this stretch in your hamstrings. If you cannot move all the way down during your first hatha yoga class, don’t worry, it takes patience and flexibility but you will get there eventually.</span></p>
<h3><span style="font-weight: 400;">4. Downward dog</span></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Still in the standing forward bend position, you’re going to move your hands forward, walking away from your feet. Push your hip up to create a triangular shape with your body. Try to keep your heels flat on the ground, but if that doesn’t work for you yet, you can relax one leg while placing the other foot flat on the ground and alternate sides. This way, you will still get the full stretch out of the downward dog pose.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0195/9310/1376/files/Move_june_397_480x480.jpg?v=1619702777" alt="Downward Dog" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"></span></p>
<h3><span style="font-weight: 400;">5. Bridge pose</span></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Last but not least in our top five hatha yoga poses, we’ll talk about the bridge pose. Lay down on your </span><a href="https://www.yogi-bare.com/collections/yoga-mats" title="Yoga mat"><span style="font-weight: 400;">yoga mat</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, on your back, and place your feet as close to your bum as possible. Next, press your hips up from the ground and hold this pose. The bridge pose improves core and lower body strength in addition to lengthening the spine. </span></p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.yogi-bare.com/blogs/find-your-y-b/easy-15-minute-calisthenics-routine-to-build-upper-body-strength</id>
    <published>2021-07-04T18:02:59-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-04T18:03:24-05:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.yogi-bare.com/blogs/find-your-y-b/easy-15-minute-calisthenics-routine-to-build-upper-body-strength"/>
    <title>Easy 15 Minute Calisthenics Routine To Build Upper Body Strength</title>
    <author>
      <name>James Oakley</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<h2>What is Calisthenics?</h2>
<p><span>You might have heard the term ‘Calisthenics’ being thrown around in conversation or read an article about it on the internet. Despite the slightly clinical name, it’s basically good old fashioned ‘keep fit’. Chances are that you’ve even done this in some other guise at the gym, within an exercise class or just hoofing around at home. </span></p>
<p><span>Calisthenics is actually a form of strength and resistance training which uses gravity and body weight. It’s come to prominence during the recent lockdowns because it’s easy, can be practised  alone and is often done outdoors. </span></p>
<br>
<h2>Benefits of Calisthenics</h2>
<p><span>Let’s face it, using the same gym equipment and machines day in, day out can get so boring. That’s why so many people lose motivation within the first three months and give up. If you’re short on time, we won’t berate you for resenting the time it takes to travel to and from the gym either.</span></p>
<p><span>Fortunately, calisthenics is a great solution to such problems. For a start, there are hundreds of exercises so every workout can be completely different. You can do it anywhere, with minimal or no equipment. If you do like a mat to prevent slipping and sliding however, we can highly recommend the </span><a href="https://www.yogi-bare.com/collections/original-paws" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><b>Yogi Bare Paws Mat</b></a><span>, our natural rubber mat for extreme grip, perfect for all those push ups too.</span></p>
<p><span>No travel is required, and this form of exercise also capitalises on the fact that our bodies were made to move. So, it’s a natural way to keep healthy! Calisthenic exercises ask more of the body in a relatively short space of time, burning more calories than a regular cardio workout. They build functional strength, making everyday tasks much easier, build stamina and endurance, and reduce stress on the joints. And to cap it all, it’s free!</span></p>
<br>
<h2>Calisthenics for Upper Body</h2>
<p><span>Having a strong upper body and core is a key aspect to keeping fit and healthy. It ensures better balance, posture, strength, stability, a healthy back, less injuries, and even tighter abdominals. </span></p>
<p><span>Calisthenics uses multiple muscles at any one time so it’s a great form of exercise for strengthening and developing muscles of the upper body, including the upper back, neck, head, chest, abdominals, arms, and shoulder. </span></p>
<br>
<h2>Quick calisthenics routine</h2>
<p><span>There are four fundamental exercises to include in a Calisthenic upper body workout:</span></p>
<ul>
<li><span>Chin-ups</span></li>
<li><span>Pull ups</span></li>
<li><span>Dips</span></li>
<li><span>Push-ups</span></li>
</ul>
<p><span>These might sound simple, and it’s true there really isn’t anything fancy about them, but they’re incredibly effective. </span></p>
<p><span>Pull ups strengthen the back, arms, shoulder, pecs, and oblique muscles. This can be a challenging exercise so if you find them difficult, even just getting into position and hanging from the bar, with an overhand grip (palms facing away) and with hands positioned on the bar just slightly outside of your shoulders for 10-30 seconds will begin to build strength. </span></p>
<p><span>To move into a full pull up, pull yourself upwards until your chin is a little above the bar. As you get more stamina over time, you could progress to the chest to bar pull up where you get your chest to the bar.</span></p>
<p><span>Although very similar, the chin-up is slightly different because you have an underhand grip (palms face towards you). This also means that your hands tend to be shoulder width or narrower.  All of the same muscles are activated as its close cousin, the pull up. However, the pectoral and bicep muscles are more engaged with this one.</span></p>
<p><span>Dips move the body up and down by hinging on the elbows. They’re particularly great for working the triceps. These can be done using gym equipment, parallel bars, dip bars (often found alongside other outdoor exercise equipment) or 2 parallel objects with a steady surface. In simple terms you dip down in a controlled movement, whilst keeping the chest upright, then pull yourself back up to complete a rep. </span></p>
<p><span>A push up, also commonly known as a press up, is used as a form of punishment in the army! It certainly requires stamina but despite its reputation, it’s fantastic as an all-round upper body exercise, targeting chest, arms, and shoulders. Start in a high plank, then controlling the movement, lower down. As you come towards the floor and chest or chin makes contact, that’s your cue to push upwards, keeping your core tight, back up to the high plank again.</span></p>
<p><span>We’d recommend incorporating at least 2 upper body workouts into your calisthenics routine per week. If you can, do 3 sets of each exercise then rest for 3 minutes. Try and do that for at least 4 rounds to feel the full benefit. If you can’t manage that to begin with, just do what you feel comfortable with and build up from there.</span></p>
<p><span>Once you’ve finished, don’t forget that you need to give your body a minimum of 2 rest days in between each upper body workout for recovery time.</span></p>
<br>
<p><span>If you enjoyed this article, </span><a href="https://www.yogi-bare.com/blogs/find-your-y-b/7-calisthenics-poses-to-increase-core-strength"><b>click here</b></a><span> for more calisthenics exercises to increase core strength. Don’t quite want to leave the yoga just yet? Why not combine it with calisthenics by reading </span><a href="https://www.yogi-bare.com/blogs/find-your-y-b/how-to-combine-yoga-and-calisthenics" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><b>‘How to Combine Yoga and Calisthenics’</b></a><b>.</b></p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.yogi-bare.com/blogs/find-your-y-b/our-top-5-favourite-sustainable-wellness-brands</id>
    <published>2021-06-28T04:27:49-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-28T04:28:00-05:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.yogi-bare.com/blogs/find-your-y-b/our-top-5-favourite-sustainable-wellness-brands"/>
    <title>Our Top 5 Favourite Sustainable Wellness Brands</title>
    <author>
      <name>James Oakley</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p><span>Here at Yogi Bare HQ, we’re very concerned about the state of our planet. Climate change, habitat destruction, polluted oceans, and skies, melting ice caps, landfill, food waste and animals at risk of extinction. Damage on an untold scale caused by the human race. Whilst we now have a greater awareness, time is rapidly running out. So much so, that the UN has warned that we need to make significant changes within the next 10 years otherwise it may be too late. So what can we do to save our planet?</span></p>
<p><span>Without doubt, we need to pay more respect to the world we inhabit. All of us have a role to play and that includes industry and individual businesses. Producing eco-friendly and sustainable products has to be the only way forward. </span><span>These are such important values to the team at Yogi Bare, that they impact on every aspect of our business. From product, to packaging to freight, every step of creating our products is carefully considered, waste minimised, and sustainable, recyclable materials used and reused wherever possible. </span></p>
<p><span>Something else we love to do is champion other businesses that are creating sustainable products too. We really believe that industries need to come together to make change happen. When we all work towards one mission, anything is possible.  </span></p>
<p><span> </span></p>
<h2>Our Top 5 Favourite Sustainable Wellness Brands</h2>
<p><span> </span></p>
<h3><a href="https://www.wearewild.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><b>WILD: Deodorant Re-Fill</b></a></h3>
<p><span>This is a brand that wants to ‘shake up our throwaway culture in the bathroom’. They’re on a mission to get us re-using deodorants and it’s not as weird as it sounds!</span></p>
<p><span><strong><a href="https://www.wearewild.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Wild</a></strong> use ingredients derived from nature rather than components like Aluminium Sulphates which actually stop your pores from sweating. The sturdy deodorant case is designed to be ‘made for life’ and once your deodorant stick is finished, you can simply replace it with a refill.  Just in case you ever want to get rid of the case, it’s been specifically made from Aluminium because it’s a material that can be recycled infinite times. </span></p>
<p><span>Wild have also chosen to offset their carbon footprint by working with </span><a href="https://www.onamission.world/partners" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><b>On a Mission</b></a><span> </span><span>to plant trees. When you purchase a deodorant, some of the money goes towards planting trees all over the world.</span></p>
<p><span> </span></p>
<h3><a href="https://staywildswim.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><b>Stay Wild: Swimwear</b></a></h3>
<p><span><strong><a href="https://staywildswim.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Stay Wild</a></strong> are committed to fighting the problem of plastic pollution by contributing to its solution. As far as they’re concerned every small detail matters, even their thread is made from rPET, a material crafted from recycled bottles.</span></p>
<p><span>This is an innovative swimwear company that combines classic, stylish designs with sustainable materials. Econyl® is made from unwanted waste including fishing nets pulled from the ocean and fabric scraps leftover from industry. Using advanced technology, the nylon is brought back to its original purity and then reused to make new products. Along with its biodegradable and eco-friendly packaging, this is swimwear with a conscience!</span></p>
<p><span> </span></p>
<h3><a href="https://scentered.me/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><b>Scentered</b></a></h3>
<p><span>Our favourite mindful <strong><a href="https://scentered.me/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">aromatherapy brand</a></strong> has made sure that all of their packaging can be repurposed, recycled, or reused. Beautifully designed, their stylish candle jars can be repurposed and brought back to life in all sorts of ways including jewellery holders, ornaments and even desk tidies. 100% recycled plastic bottles are used for their hair and body care range, saving more plastic from landfill. The candle jars are made from glass meaning they too can be recycled if you don’t wish to repurpose them.</span></p>
<p><span>When it comes to detail, this brand is spot on. They’re so dedicated to repurposing waste that they even use offcuts of tea bag production to cushion their products whilst in transit. Not only that, but this forward- thinking brand is now disrupting the market with their clever aromatherapy balm refills and therapy candle refills, again prolonging product lifespan, and reducing the need for more packaging. </span></p>
<p><span> </span></p>
<h3><a href="https://supernovaliving.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><b>Supernova: Protein</b></a></h3>
<p><span>These pioneers of wellness powder are creating a buzz in all the right places. Vogue, Grazia, Women’s Health. You name it, they’re in it! These incredible <strong><a href="https://supernovaliving.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">vegan protein powders</a></strong> are made from organic plant proteins and adaptogens to replenish the body and mind.</span></p>
<p><span>How is organic farming better for the planet? It’s because organic products are more energy efficient than traditional farming methods and produce less emissions. Ultimately, it means that the carbon footprint for organic farming is lower compared to intensive farming. Another benefit is that there is less risk of pollution to soil and our waterways too.</span></p>
<p><span>It’s believed that nature-friendly farming along with other key changes to our food systems could have a positive impact on global warming. So these organic powders not only are great for our health but also that of the planet too!</span></p>
<p><span> </span></p>
<h3><a href="https://lastobject.com/?gclid=CjwKCAjww-CGBhALEiwAQzWxOlTouRSo3XDpK4KLfEyUhUgIGG98MLshWvGtGaqjmd0ozZ8r-aavERoCadgQAvD_BwE" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><b>LastObject</b></a></h3>
<p><span>Designer Isabel Aagaard was frustrated with the single use culture, so she decided to do something about it. Her mission was to create reusable sustainable alternatives. LastObject only launched its first product in 2019 but already it has LastSwab (alternative to cotton buds), LastRound (alternative to make-up pads) and LastTissue (alternative to paper tissues). </span></p>
<p><span>This is an elegantly designed range of personal care products that will enhance the look of any bathroom. These don’t just look beautiful though. They are cleverly designed solutions to wasteful habits. Did you know, for example, that the average person can go through hundreds of paper or cotton buds a year? During their manufacture, raw materials are used, and harmful CO2 is created, then after use, they’re discarded and end up in landfill. </span></p>
<p><span><strong><a href="https://lastobject.com/?gclid=CjwKCAjww-CGBhALEiwAQzWxOlTouRSo3XDpK4KLfEyUhUgIGG98MLshWvGtGaqjmd0ozZ8r-aavERoCadgQAvD_BwE" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">LastObject’s</a></strong> products are end-to-end sustainable and exceptionally high quality, providing consumers that are keen to do their bit for the environment with a viable alternative to single use products. If we all shared Isabel’s vision, just imagine the impact that would have on reducing global waste.</span></p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.yogi-bare.com/blogs/find-your-y-b/finally-going-places-take-a-travel-yoga-mat</id>
    <published>2021-06-22T03:50:38-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-22T03:50:48-05:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.yogi-bare.com/blogs/find-your-y-b/finally-going-places-take-a-travel-yoga-mat"/>
    <title>Finally Going Places? Take A Travel Yoga Mat</title>
    <author>
      <name>James Oakley</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p><span>At long last, we’re all finally moving again! And I don’t mean from the sofa to the biscuit cupboard. The last year has been unbelievably hard in so many ways, the necessary restrictions enforcing us to stay put have been a particularly difficult infringement to tolerate. It caused havoc to businesses, disrupted holidays and worst of all, prevented us from seeing our loved ones. </span></p>
<p><span>Thankfully, the hard work seems to have paid off and as restrictions are easing, we’re venturing further afield, once more able to meet up with our friends and family and fully appreciating the true beauty of the English countryside.</span></p>
<br>
<h2>Travel Yoga Mat</h2>
<p><span>It feels liberating to once more have the freedom to move around the country again. That said, it can impact our life in other ways. We’ve all got used to a certain routine and having more time at home. Now, we’re much more likely to stay away from home for work purposes, plan overnight stays or weekends away and of course, staycations are back on too. </span></p>
<p><span>If you’ve spent lockdown creating a yoga habit, you needn’t worry that your yoga routine will be disrupted. Sure, you may need to change the day, time, and place, but you can still do it! Rest assured that Yogi Bare has got your back covered so that your yoga won’t suffer. We’ve created the perfect yoga mat to facilitate your practise wherever you might be.</span></p>
<br>
<h2>Yoga Mat to Take on Holiday</h2>
<p><span>Any yoga devotee won’t want to forgo their practise during holiday-time. It’s such a wonderful form of exercise because you can do it alone, anywhere in the world. And you always feel better after yoga too. </span></p>
<p><span>The great thing is that you only really need a yoga mat to get going. Its best to use one because slipping and sliding can be dangerous and is a common cause of injury. A non-slip yoga mat will put a stop to that and minimise any risk of an accident. Not only that, but it will also support your joints, balance, and posture. </span></p>
<p><span>Our </span><a href="https://www.yogi-bare.com/collections/yoga-mats/Teddy" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><b>Teddy Mat</b></a><span> </span><span>is</span><span> </span><span>a wonderfully lightweight, high-performance non-slip yoga mat that can be transported literally anywhere. It can be used inside or outside, on any surface including floor, grass, or sand, whatever takes your fancy. After all, you’re on holiday. As they say, anything goes! This yoga mat offers expert grip ensuring you feel fully confident wherever you are practising your yoga. That makes it the ultimate must-have holiday yoga mat!</span></p>
<br>
<h2>Lightweight Yoga Mat</h2>
<p><span>The </span><a href="https://www.yogi-bare.com/collections/yoga-mats/Teddy" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><b>Teddy Mat</b></a><b><span> </span>is<span> </span></b><span>foldable into a small square so that you can put it into a bag or suitcase and is as light as a feather (well almost) at 1.5kg which makes it portable enough to take on holiday. So, whether it’s a staycation or vacation, this is the yoga mat to add to your packing list.</span></p>
<br>
<h2>Yoga Mat to Take to Classes</h2>
<p><span>We’re all a bit obsessed about not sharing germs at the moment and for good reason. Sharing yoga mats does have the potential for germs to be passed on, especially Plantar Warts, Athlete’s Foot, Cold and Flu as well as Covid-19. So, it’s a good idea to bring your own mat to group classes, negating the need to use one from the studio or health club. Even more reason to get a </span><a href="https://www.yogi-bare.com/collections/yoga-mats/Teddy" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><b>Teddy Mat</b></a><b>!</b></p>
<p><span>Thinking more widely, because of its portability and supreme grip, you can use our Teddy Mat for any form of exercise including calisthenics, Pilates, abs workouts, stretching and if you’re brave enough, hot yoga.</span></p>
<br>
<h2>How Does the<span> </span><a href="https://www.yogi-bare.com/collections/yoga-mats/Teddy" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Teddy Mat</a><span> </span>Work?</h2>
<p><span>This exceptionally designed travel yoga mat incorporates a velvet microfiber surface that becomes very grippy under sweat and moisture. At the same time, the strong natural sustainable rubber base grips to the floor, preventing bunching up. </span></p>
<p><span>The </span><a href="https://www.yogi-bare.com/collections/yoga-mats/Teddy" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><b>Teddy Mat</b></a><span> </span><span>comes in three attractive designs, which are just perfect for giving you a dose of inspiration and reminding you that exercise should feel fun and enjoyable. Choose from Tropical, Cosmic or Nevada.</span></p>
<p><span> </span></p>
<h2>How to Clean Your<span> </span><a href="https://www.yogi-bare.com/collections/yoga-mats/Teddy" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Teddy Mat</a>
</h2>
<p><span>When you travel, you tend to pick up more grime, sweat  and germs and yoga mats, unfortunately, are not the exception. It’s therefore important to regularly clean and maintain your yoga mat. Thank goodness that the </span><a href="https://www.yogi-bare.com/collections/yoga-mats/Teddy" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><b>Teddy Mat</b></a><span> </span><span>is very easy to clean and bring back to its full glory. </span></p>
<p><span>To give it a spruce up,  put the mat on a quick wash in your washing machine at 30/40 degrees with a small amount of detergent. To dry, hang it up and store it out of direct sunlight. It’s so super simple!</span></p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.yogi-bare.com/blogs/find-your-y-b/fathers-day-wellness-gift-guide-2021</id>
    <published>2021-06-03T02:30:01-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-03T02:30:01-05:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.yogi-bare.com/blogs/find-your-y-b/fathers-day-wellness-gift-guide-2021"/>
    <title>Father&apos;s Day Wellness Gift Guide 2021</title>
    <author>
      <name>James Oakley</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">It’s that time of the year to pamper and spoil your father with gifts to show him your love, gratitude or simply because it’s Father’s Day. The third Sunday in June is always a special moment to spend with your family, in particular your father. If you haven’t found your dad a perfect gift yet, we got your back! Lockdown has definitely taken its toll on all of us, so it’s okay for men to feel more rundown after the covid outbreak. The past year has increased our stress levels and made us feel less ourselves. We have created a wellness gift guide for fathers who could use a moment of ultimate relaxation for this Father’s Day 2021.</span></p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">Yoga mat to help with meditation or yoga practice</span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">If your dad is into yoga and meditation or if you think it would benefit both his mental and physical health, a </span><a href="https://www.yogi-bare.com/collections/yoga-mats" title="Yoga mat"><span style="font-weight: 400;">yoga mat</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> is the perfect Father’s Day gift. A yoga practice or meditation session can help to reduce stress levels and can benefit mental health. Your dad might be completely new to yoga and meditation but that’s completely fine. All he needs is a yoga mat to get started and some guidance on which poses he can do. Our </span><a href="https://www.yogi-bare.com/blogs/find-your-y-b/beginners-guide-to-yoga-for-men" title="Beginners guide to yoga for men"><span style="font-weight: 400;">beginner’s guide to yoga for men</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> can be very helpful here!</span></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0195/9310/1376/files/paws-x_480x480.jpg?v=1622617109" alt="Paws X Yoga Mat"> </p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The yoga mat we would highly recommend for your father is the </span><a href="https://www.yogi-bare.com/products/yogi-bare-paws-x-yoga-mat" title="Paws X yoga mat"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Paws X yoga mat</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, as it’s a bit wider and longer than a normal yoga mat. This will give your father enough space to move around freely. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Paws X mat also has innovative grip technology where the natural rubber is perforated to give you intense grip when you need it most. This reduces the risk of slipping or falling during your father’s first yoga session, which might come in handy.</span></p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">Sports watch to track activity</span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">A true sportsman will love this gift, but this would also be a great gift for a beginner at yoga or an outdoor sports lover. A sports watch is very handy and fun to use to keep track of your activities. Whether it’s a FitBit or Apple Watch, that’s all up to you. The fun part about a sports watch is that you can see your progress as you’re working out. If your dad is new to yoga, a sports watch will be a great help to track his improvements. </span></p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">Acupressure mat to relieve stress</span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">If the past few months have been particularly stressful for your dad, this might be the greatest gift of all: an acupressure mat. You might have heard of acupressure or acupuncture before and with this mat, it’s possible to experience its benefits from the comfort of your own home. An acupressure mat uses thin plastic spikes to target pressure points and nerves in your body, which helps to relieve stress and body discomfort. Acupressure has proven to be effective in reducing stress, anxiety, migraines and neck and back issues. </span></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"> <img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0195/9310/1376/files/acupressure_mat_480x480.jpg?v=1622617130" alt="Acupressure mat"></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This Father’s Day, gift your dad an </span><a href="https://www.yogi-bare.com/collections/acupressure/Acupressure-mat" title="Acupressure mat"><span style="font-weight: 400;">acupressure mat</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> to help him to relieve stress and tension in his body. Trust us, he will be forever grateful for this thoughtful and effective gift!</span></p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">Aromatherapy to help him relax</span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Finally, aromatherapy products make a great gift and are very thoughtful to help your father wind down after a busy year. Aromatherapy uses essential oils in different scents that target the limbic system of your brain. This part of your brain </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">supports a variety of functions including emotion, behavior and long-term memory. If your dad could use a bit of relaxation and de-stressing, we recommend gifting the </span><a href="https://scentered.com/collections/de-stress/products/i-want-to-de-stress-gift-set" title="De-stress aromatherapy gift set"><span style="font-weight: 400;">DE-STRESS Aromatherapy Gift Set</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> by Scentered. This gift set contains a balm and candle that will help your father to feel less stressed and more at peace. After all, a bit of me-time is the best present anyone could receive, right?</span></p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.yogi-bare.com/blogs/find-your-y-b/how-to-get-over-post-lockdown-gym-anxiety</id>
    <published>2021-06-01T03:52:57-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-23T10:11:45-05:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.yogi-bare.com/blogs/find-your-y-b/how-to-get-over-post-lockdown-gym-anxiety"/>
    <title>How To Get Over Post Lockdown Gym Anxiety</title>
    <author>
      <name>James Oakley</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">As COVID restrictions are lifting, many of us are turning our thoughts to getting fit once more. But after months at home, the prospect of joining a gym, class or even doing some exercise on our own can feel daunting and off-putting. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"> </span></p>
<h2>Post Lockdown Gym Anxiety</h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">We’ve not had to interact with large groups of people for over a year. So, it’s no surprise that social anxiety is at an all-time high right now. Naturally, we’re all still feeling concerned about </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">COVID-19 too.</span> <span style="font-weight: 400;">But with the vaccine roll out well underway, and restrictions lifting, the gyms are ready for us! The fact that we may feel out of shape or less physically fit than previously means that it can seem like a big mountain to climb - but you can do it!</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">It’s perfectly okay and completely normal to feel a bit scared of returning to the gym or whatever form of exercise is your preference. Be comforted by the fact that you’re not the only one. Millions of people are feeling exactly the same way too. In fact, at this time, mental wellness, above everything else, is paramount. We should all be giving ourselves and others a bit of self-love and understanding. Don’t pile loads of pressure on yourself. Accept that it’s unlikely you’ll hit peak performance from the get-go because improving physical fitness takes time after all.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Breaking things down into small steps is a great way to begin. Think of doing a ten-minute run rather than ten miles. A daily walk with a friend. An exercise class on your TV subscription service if you’d prefer not to leave the house. These are all small ways you can dip your toe into the world of exercise. And with each small accomplishment, you can feel proud, and this will serve to build up your motivation and confidence. </span></p>
<p> </p>
<h2>Yoga for Everyone</h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Stepping into a gym with perfectly honed gym bunnies or muscle-bound alpha males may not be your idea of a good time. It’s not mine either, frankly. That’s why at Yogi Bare, we’re very keen to promote that yoga is a fantastic form of exercise accessible to everyone, no matter your size, shape, or physical ability. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Yoga attends to your body, breathing and mind, all at the same time, so it can prove useful for just about anyone. You can do yoga with your seven-year-old son or your ninety-year-old mum, after time in lockdown,</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> it’s time to reconnect, bring your family and loved ones into your yoga sessions, you may just find a shared hobby.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The great thing is that you can go at your own pace and there’s always the opportunity to opt in or out of stretches and poses. If you don’t want to try something, do a more or less advanced variation or a completely different pose altogether. The point is that you’re moving around and doing static and dynamic stretching, which is highly beneficial for your health and wellbeing.</span></p>
<p> </p>
<h2>Benefits of Yoga</h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Yoga encompasses so much. There are many different styles, and they vary from being mindful, relaxing, spiritual, and focused to being a much more physically demanding, complete cardiovascular workout. You can always find a style to suit your preference and to meet your individual needs.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Yoga can also help relieve pain, reduce muscle tension, improve circulation, and blood flow, energise you and help to improve mental health. The health and well-being benefits seem endless. It makes you wonder why it’s not on the national curriculum in schools or used more in the workplace. Whatever you need to get out of it, you can. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Another fantastic benefit is that you can do it at home, within a class or make use of the great outdoors. There are no limitations. All you need is yourself and a non-slip mat and job’s a good'un. For something a bit different, we recommend the<span> </span></span><a href="https://www.yogi-bare.com/products/yogi-bare-plant-a-tree-mathttps://www.yogi-bare.com/products/yogi-bare-plant-a-tree-mat" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><b>Wild Paws</b></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"><span> </span>non-slip yoga mat. We love it because a tree is planted for each mat sold so you can get fit, whilst doing your bit for the planet. What’s not to love!!!</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">It’s also a great idea to have your own mat for hygiene purposes. Sharing mats allows germs to be passed on, especially Plantar Warts, Athlete’s Foot, Cold and Flu as well as COVID-19. If you’re planning on returning to the studio or any group exercise class for that matter, stay safe and prevent the spread by bringing your own mat. </span></p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.yogi-bare.com/blogs/find-your-y-b/5-things-improving-your-flexibility-can-do-for-your-mental-health</id>
    <published>2021-05-25T05:20:13-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-05-25T05:22:12-05:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.yogi-bare.com/blogs/find-your-y-b/5-things-improving-your-flexibility-can-do-for-your-mental-health"/>
    <title>5 Things Improving Your Flexibility Can Do For Your Mental Health</title>
    <author>
      <name>James Oakley</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In a world where we’re increasingly spending more of our time rooted to a screen of some description, flexibility is critical for our health and wellbeing. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">But what does the word flexibility mean? Often confused with stretching, suppleness, or mobility, flexibility is in fact, the ability of our muscles and its connective tissues to stretch temporarily. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">A combination of static and dynamic stretching is the best way of improving flexibility. To many people, this will conjure up images of yoga. Whilst it’s true that stretching is a key component of yoga, stretching is also an impactful practice in its own right.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"> </span></p>
<h2>Why does Flexibility Improve Mental Health?</h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Undoubtedly, standing or sitting in one position or carrying out repetitive tasks for long periods of time takes its toll on our bodies. Hunched shoulders, RSI, aching muscles, backache, neckache, the list goes on. All this body tension translates into tight, inflexible muscles. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Experiencing aches, pains, and muscle tension can also affect our feelings and emotions and ultimately our mental health. It’s not unusual to experience fatigue, or feel completely fed up, tense, stressed or depressed and in worst cases, ill as a result of physical issues. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Stretching stimulates receptors in the nervous system that slow the production of stress hormones and lift your mood. Not just that, but better flexibility can encourage circulation and blood flow, boost energy levels and athletic performance, improve posture, and increase your range of motion. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">It’s also quick, easy, and ultra-convenient. You can literally stretch anywhere. You don’t even have to get up to do it, although it's better if you do!</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Even just a few minutes of stretching a day can make a huge difference to your flexibility. Check out our blog post<span> </span></span><b>‘</b><a href="https://www.yogi-bare.com/blogs/find-your-y-b/how-yoga-can-help-you-get-into-a-full-splits" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><b>How Yoga Can Get You into the Full Splits.’</b></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"><span> </span>By adopting a regular stretching routine, some people even achieve this within one month!</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"> </span></p>
<h2>5 Benefits of Stretching</h2>
<h3>Hormones </h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Stretching releases chemicals known as endorphins. These ‘happy’ hormones are famed for giving us a ‘high’ or euphoric feeling. Whilst the high may be short-lived, the benefits are long-lasting and those that experience endorphins regularly tend to have a more positive outlook, feel happier and their perception of pain is reduced too.</span></p>
<p><b> </b></p>
<h3>Mindfulness</h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Stretching brings a much greater awareness of the body and of any tension that’s being held within it. This is significant because it enables you to address aches, pains, and tension and take pre-emptive action before they get worse.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">A good stretch also forces you to slow your rate of breathing right down and to inhale more deeply. The more oxygen is breathed into the body, the more nourishment it receives, keeping our body at optimum health. Slower, deeper breathing also relaxes muscles, reducing tension in the body and leads to a more calm, peaceful state of mind.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">When you hold a stretch or a yoga pose, it also requires a lot of focus and brings you back to the present. This banishes the all-too often present monkey mind and because you’re concentrating on doing one thing really well, a natural side-effect is that the mind becomes less distracted. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"> </span></p>
<h3>Blood Flow</h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Stretching improves blood flow and circulation to the brain and muscles. The physical effects are obvious, blood and oxygen are delivered more quickly to muscles, tissues and cells which means a physically healthier, more youthful body. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">There are also benefits for your mental health too. It’s like an instant pick-me up. A boost to circulation and blood-flow makes you feel more energised, more clear-headed, and if you’re having a grumpy day, it's sure to lift your mood.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"> </span></p>
<h3>Improve Quality of Sleep</h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">We all know that sleep is very much linked to our mental health. When sleep suffers, we suffer. Stretching promotes mindfulness and relaxation which have been shown to settle the mind and promote better sleep. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Feeling physically comfortable without aches and pains is also important for achieving a restful night of sleep. This is where stretching can help again because it relieves muscle tension and reduces the potential for cramps. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"> </span></p>
<h3>Routine<b> </b>
</h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Adding stretching into your daily routine gives you a sense of purpose and a reason to wake up in the morning. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Studies have also shown that daily routines have a multitude of mental health benefits including creating a sense of discipline and structure, a feeling of being in control, reducing stress and anxiety, and even management of certain mental disorders. Stretching is a great way to start off the day with meaning and a calm mindset. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"> </span></p>
<h2>What Equipment Do You Need for Stretching?</h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The good news is that you don’t need much apart from yourself and a non-slip mat. It’s recommended to use one because it will support joints, balance and posture and there’s much less likelihood of injury.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">We’d recommend trying our<span> </span></span><a href="https://www.yogi-bare.com/collections/original-paws" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><b>Yogi-Bare Paws Non-slip Mat</b></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"><span> </span>for extreme grip technology or if you prefer a wider mat,<span> </span></span><a href="https://www.yogi-bare.com/products/yogi-bare-paws-x-yoga-mat" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><b>Yogi-Bare Paws X Non-slip Mat</b></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.yogi-bare.com/blogs/find-your-y-b/how-does-acupressure-help-neck-strain-from-working-at-a-desk-all-day</id>
    <published>2021-05-21T06:30:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-05-24T06:31:59-05:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.yogi-bare.com/blogs/find-your-y-b/how-does-acupressure-help-neck-strain-from-working-at-a-desk-all-day"/>
    <title>How Does Acupressure Help Neck Strain From Working At A Desk All Day</title>
    <author>
      <name>James Oakley</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">It wasn’t long after beginning this blogpost that I realised that all the points that I was planning to cover, applied to me. Of course, being a writer means that I spend most of my time hunched over a desk, staring at my laptop, tapping away or if I’m not doing that, I’m on the phone, discussing my next job with someone. So, there normally comes a point in the day where I realise that my shoulders are up by my ears and my poor neck feels like it’s lost all mobility because it’s that tight. The other thing is that it really, really aches. As does my back, glutes, and hips, not to mention the RSI in my wrists and arms. Sitting at a desk, especially one that’s not been ergonomically designed, for a prolonged period, is quite clearly not good for us.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Things that are good for us are getting up and having a break, stretching, exercise, yoga, massage, and acupressure. Trouble is, even though we know this to be the case, we get drawn into what we’re doing, or after being bombarded with an influx of emails, we inexplicably become cemented to the spot, eager to clear down our never-ending to-do list and simply forget to pause and take a break.</span></p>
<br>
<h2>What is Acupressure?</h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This is an<span> </span></span><span style="font-weight: 400;">ancient Chinese healing therapy that promotes relaxation, wellness and easing of muscle tension. Not only that, but it’s also been found to soothe aches, chronic pain and ease migraine and cranial tension, which can, of course, be exacerbated by neck strain from staring at a computer all day long.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Some liken acupressure to acupuncture without needles. Traditional Chinese medical theory describes acupoints which lie along meridians, or energy channels in the body. The belief is that energy or qi (ch’i) flows through the 12 major invisible channels and these connect a network of organs which interact and communicate with each other.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">When a meridian is blocked, it’s thought that this puts the body out of kilter and it no longer works optimally, causing aches, pain, fatigue and in the worst case, illness, or disease. Acupressure works to restore balance in the body by clearing blockages within the meridians. A practitioner typically uses their fingers, palms, elbows and even feet to apply pressure to acupoints along the body’s meridians. </span></p>
<br>
<h2>How Does an Acupressure Pillow Help with Neck Strain?</h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">There are literally hundreds of acupressure points on the body. That’s why Yogi Bare’s ingeniously designed<span> </span></span><a href="https://www.yogi-bare.com/collections/acupressure" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><b>Acupressure Pillow</b></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"><span> </span>has 210 pressure points. That’s a lot of points!</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Essentially, this acupressure pillow works on the same principle as acupuncture. It’s covered in painless round plastic spikes that create gentle but deep tissue stimulation, applying pressure to various points of the neck where acupuncture would normally apply a needle. This results in a release of muscle tension, easing aches and pains in the shoulder and neck area. </span></p>
<p> </p>
<h2>How to Use a Yogi Bare Acupressure Mat</h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">If you’re suffering relentless aches and pains from too much time on the computer or phone, it’s time to apply some much-needed self-care. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">To get the full benefit, use the<span> </span></span><a href="https://www.yogi-bare.com/collections/acupressure"><b>Yogi Bare Acupressure Pillow</b></a><a href="https://www.yogi-bare.co.uk/collections/acupressure/products/yogi-bare-acupressure-pillow-black-pillow-of-nails-for-tension-relief-and-deep-relaxation"><span style="font-weight: 400;">,</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"><span> </span>alongside a<span> </span></span><a href="https://www.yogi-bare.com/collections/acupressure" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><b>Yogi Bare Acupressure Mat</b></a><span> </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">20-40 minutes several times a week. The complete<span> </span></span><a href="https://www.yogi-bare.com/collections/acupressure" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><b>Acupressure Set</b></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, containing an acupressure mat and pillow is your perfect antidote to a day spent on the laptop, sitting at a desk or holding a phone between your ear and neck (you know you really shouldn’t do that).</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Using an acupressure pillow and mat also means that you can create a wonderful relaxation routine, targeting all the areas of your body that need help to unwind. To enhance the experience, why not light a candle, put on some soothing music, or meditate whilst you use your acupressure pillow?</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">It’s important to experiment with the position of your acupressure pillow until you get the right sensation and level of comfort for you. Position the pillow in the neck crevice behind the head. After use, keep hydrated because acupressure will be stimulating and is likely to kickstart your body’s detoxifying process.<span> </span></span>Click here<span style="font-weight: 400;"><span> </span>for more on the<span> </span><a href="https://www.yogi-bare.com/blogs/find-your-y-b/10-benefits-of-using-an-acupuncture-mat" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><strong>benefits of an acupressure mat</strong></a><strong>.</strong></span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Be amazed at how this ancient technique can help address 21</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">st</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><span> </span>century health and wellbeing issues. We promise you won’t look back once you experience the benefits from using a Yogi Bare Acupressure pillow and mat. </span></p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.yogi-bare.com/blogs/find-your-y-b/natural-rubber-yoga-mats-vs-synthetic-yoga-mats</id>
    <published>2021-05-17T05:27:04-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-05-17T05:27:04-05:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.yogi-bare.com/blogs/find-your-y-b/natural-rubber-yoga-mats-vs-synthetic-yoga-mats"/>
    <title>Natural Rubber Yoga Mats vs Synthetic Yoga Mats</title>
    <author>
      <name>James Oakley</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The beauty of a yoga mat is that it’s multi-purpose. So, whether exercise, yoga, or meditation, is your thing, having one of these on hand means you can do it at home, on the move or within a class environment. If you’re still borrowing a mat, it’s time to think about purchasing your own one. Think of the greater flexibility you’ll have and the extra reassurance using your own mat will bring during this Covid-19 era. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Choosing the right yoga mat is important though, so do look at the options before you make a purchase. There have been many advancements made in the technology and materials used for yoga mats. Also, with eco-consciousness at the forefront of everyone’s mind, some offer a sustainable option too.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"> </span></p>
<h2>Synthetic Yoga Mats</h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Synthetic mats tend to be made from PVC. Whilst this material is cheap and relatively durable, there have been some concerns about PVC raised, linking it to health issues, including headaches, nausea, allergic reactions and even diseases like cancer. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Another downside to PVC is that it’s not an eco-friendly material and is hardly ever recycled. The major issue is that it's burnt on landfill, releasing dangerous toxins into the atmosphere. Some of these chemicals are greenhouse gases, which can also affect climate change. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Unfortunately, polyester mats are not much better either. The sad fact is that polyester production is energy intensive, meaning that it’s another cause of greenhouse gas emissions and contamination of the earth’s water too. In short, the cheapest yoga mat is not always the best one in terms of our health or for the planet. Eco-friendly materials tend to be a little more costly so how can we be sure that we’re getting our money’s worth?</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"> </span></p>
<h2>Natural Rubber Mats</h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Luckily, you don’t need to be on a complete downer after reading about the impact of synthetic mats. There is some very good news because by opting for one made from natural materials, toxicity and the impact on the planet can be minimised. A yoga mat made from natural rubber, means that you’re purchasing something free from harmful chemical residues and a material that’s sustainable. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Being eco-conscious and creating sustainable products is at the core of everything we do at Yogi Bare. Every step along the way, from product, to packaging to freight has been micro- analysed, waste is minimised, and sustainable, recyclable materials are used and reused wherever possible. Even the attractive designs on our yoga mats are laser engraved to avoid the use of anything toxic.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">And Yogi Bare yoga mats are made from biodegradable, natural rubber, sourced from a sustainable forest. We’ve also collaborated on a fantastic initiative at Moy Tree Farm to support their Project Hometree. A tree is planted for each<span> </span></span><a href="https://www.yogi-bare.com/products/yogi-bare-plant-a-tree-mat" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Wild Paws</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"><span> </span>non-slip yoga mat sold. Brilliantly designed, this mat encapsulates our eco-ethos with images of trees, swallows, and fauna, allowing the user to practise yoga feeling happy that they’ve contributed to improving the planet. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"> </span></p>
<h2>Are Yogi Bare Natural Rubber Mats Any Good?</h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"> </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Natural rubber is great because it doesn’t split or crack when you roll it up and it’s a material with highly grippy properties. This ensures that our non-slip yoga mats are high-performance, with an infinitely better grip, and a 4mm thickness. There’s no slipping and sliding around, when you’re trying to stay in pose with our yoga mats. That’s because<span> </span></span><span style="font-weight: 400;">sweat doesn’t make our mats slippery, in fact, it improves grip!</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Yogi Bare mats are also thicker, bouncier and way more comfortable than a traditional synthetic yoga mat. The thickness is an important feature because it supports the impact on ankles, wrists, and knees. Providing crucial joint support helps the user to improve their balance meaning there’s less likelihood of injury. A positive knock-on effect is that it also gives the user confidence to hold stronger poses and try those more challenging ones because they’re not anxious about sliding out of the pose. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Natural rubber also has the added advantage that it’s ridiculously easy to clean. Our<span> </span></span><a href="https://www.yogi-bare.com/collections/original-paws" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><b>Paws</b></a><b>,<span> </span></b><a href="https://www.yogi-bare.com/products/yogi-bare-paws-x-yoga-mat" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><b>Paws X</b></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"><span> </span>and<span> </span></span><a href="https://www.yogi-bare.com/products/yogi-bare-plant-a-tree-mat" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><b>Wild Paws</b></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"><span> </span>mats can be cleaned once weekly by wiping down both sides with warm water diluted with completely natural fresh lemon juice! This cleans away any built-up oils and dirt, leaving these long-lasting mats in pristine condition. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"> </span></p>
<h2>Which Yogi Bare Mat Should I Choose?</h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">We think that choosing a natural rubber yoga mat is a no-brainer. The only choice you must make is which one to buy!</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">For those that prefer a classic style yoga mat, opt for extreme grip with<span> </span></span><a href="https://www.yogi-bare.com/collections/original-paws" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><b>Paws</b></a><span> </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">or<span> </span></span><a href="https://www.yogi-bare.com/products/yogi-bare-plant-a-tree-mat" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><b>Wild Paws</b></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Alternatively, the<span> </span></span><a href="https://www.yogi-bare.com/products/yogi-bare-teddy-yoga-mat-luxury-velvet-feel-sweat-adaptive-mat" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><b>Tropical Teddy Mat</b></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"><span> </span>or<span> </span></span><a href="https://www.yogi-bare.com/products/yogi-bare-teddy-yoga-mat-luxury-velvet-feel-sweat-adaptive-mat-stars" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><b>Cosmic Teddy Mat</b></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"><span> </span>are perfect for yoga on the move, hot yoga, when you travel,  holiday time or if you’re just up for a funky design. </span></p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.yogi-bare.com/blogs/find-your-y-b/7-calisthenics-poses-to-increase-core-strength</id>
    <published>2021-05-13T08:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-05-13T08:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.yogi-bare.com/blogs/find-your-y-b/7-calisthenics-poses-to-increase-core-strength"/>
    <title>7 Calisthenics Poses To Increase Core Strength</title>
    <author>
      <name>James Oakley</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">For some, Calisthenics is a well known form of exercise but for others, this might be the first time you hear of it. Calisthenics is a form of exercise that only uses gravity and body weight, meaning you don't need any equipment. It’s a great way of strength and resistance training and can be done anywhere. Especially during spring and summer, Calisthenics is the perfect workout as it can easily be performed outside. If you’re a lover of yoga and you enjoy working out outside more than anything, we definitely recommend trying out Calisthenics. In this blog, we will guide you through seven Calisthenics poses that help you to increase your core strength. </span></p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">Calisthenics to gain core strength </span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">No need for a gym membership, equipment or other special workout gear, you simply need your body. And a bit of motivation would come in handy. With Calisthenics, you use your entire body weight to exercise which helps you to gain core strength. Doing specific exercises targeting the core, Calisthenics will help you to define your core muscles and gain more strength. Besides the fact that gaining core strength will help you to define muscles, it will also help you during your Calisthenics workouts as most poses require strength from your core. If you’re looking for a </span><a href="https://www.yogi-bare.com/blogs/find-your-y-b/beginner-s-at-home-calisthenics-20-minute-workout" title="Beginner Calisthenics workout"><span style="font-weight: 400;">20 minute beginner Calisthenics workout</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, we have you covered. </span></p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">Calisthenics poses targeting your core</span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Now, let’s talk about Calisthenics poses that specifically target your core. We have gathered the best seven poses that will help you to gain core strength. </span></p>
<h3><span style="font-weight: 400;">1.  Hollow Body Hold</span></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Starting off with an intense exercise: the Hollow Body Hold. Lie down on your back on the floor and put your arms and legs straightened in the air. Now, hover both your arms and legs above the ground, without actually touching the ground. Yes, that’s going to burn! Hold this pose for as long as possible and repeat it three times. </span></p>
<h3><span style="font-weight: 400;">2. V-Hold</span></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Another exercise that is an absolute killer for your abs is the V-hold. As the name of the exercise might suggest, you’re going to place your body into a V-shape. Sit down and lift your legs straightened in the air at a 45 degree angle. If this is too hard for you, you can keep your hands placed on the ground beside you. Again, hold this pose for as long as you can and repeat it three times. </span></p>
<h3><span style="font-weight: 400;">3. Plank Hold</span></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">We are sincerely sorry for this one, but it is a must. It’s probably safe to say that we all have a love-hate relationship with the Plank Hold. Arguably the best exercise to gain core strength, but also one of the hardest one to perform. Time has probably never passed this slowly. But you can do this! Hold the Plank position for as long as you can, have a short rest in between and repeat this three times. </span></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-weight: 400;"><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0195/9310/1376/files/calisthenics_480x480.jpg?v=1620736722" alt="Calisthenics "></span></p>
<h3><span style="font-weight: 400;">4. Superman Hold</span></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The next exercise will make you feel like a true superhero. Start in a plank position with your arms straightened and lift one arm and its opposite leg up in the air. Without switching sides, hold this position for as long as possible. Next, bring your arm and leg down and switch sides. Repeat this three times per side. </span></p>
<h3><span style="font-weight: 400;">5. Ab roller</span></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Even though you don’t necessarily need equipment for Calisthenics, you could use an ab roller to intensify your workout. An ab roller is a small wheel that you roll forwards with your hands. Sit down on your knees and lower your upper body by using the ab roller. This is a great exercise for your entire core! Slowly move up and down and repeat this five times. </span></p>
<h3><span style="font-weight: 400;">6. Back Extension</span></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Keep going, the end of your workout is near. Now that we have worked our abs, it’s time to focus on the back muscles. It’s important to exercise your entire core to gain the most strength. For the Back Extension, lie down on your stomach with your head facing the floor. Extend your arms in front of you and slowly lift your legs and arms. Hold this position for as long as you can and repeat it three times. </span></p>
<h3><span style="font-weight: 400;">7. Cobra Hold</span></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Lastly, we’re going to target the upper back muscles by doing the Cobra Hold. Lie down on your stomach and slowly lift your upper body as far as you can. Keep your legs pressed into the floor. Hold this position for as long as you can and for the last time, repeat it three times.</span> </p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">And… RELAX, you’re done. You have definitely earned a bit of rest now. And don’t forget to hydrate!</span></p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.yogi-bare.com/blogs/find-your-y-b/10-grounding-activities-to-release-stress</id>
    <published>2021-05-10T05:30:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-05-12T05:16:48-05:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.yogi-bare.com/blogs/find-your-y-b/10-grounding-activities-to-release-stress"/>
    <title>10 Grounding Activities To Release Stress</title>
    <author>
      <name>James Oakley</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p><span>When we think about stress and anxiety, we often veer towards traditional coping strategies. Mindfulness, meditation, exercise and stress-counselling. These all have their place and can be highly beneficial. But did you ever consider doing more everyday activities to ground yourself? </span></p>
<p><span>Sometimes we get so caught up in life that we even forget to take a breath. But it doesn’t have to be like that. Just by taking mindful pauses, we can begin to notice the little things in life that promote a sense of wellbeing. Not only that, but we cultivate a sense of gratitude for them, which as we’re coming to understand, is associated with happiness. </span></p>
<p><span> </span></p>
<h2>Mental Health Awareness Week 2021</h2>
<p><span>We have to put our mental health first. No question. That’s why </span><a href="https://www.mentalhealth.org.uk/campaigns/mental-health-awareness-week" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><b>Mental Health Awareness Week</b></a><span> </span><span>runs every year, to provide a focus on this massive issue, and keep it at the forefront of our collective mind-set. </span><a href="https://www.mentalhealth.org.uk/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><b>Mentalhealth.org</b></a><span> also have some excellent resources and tips on their website. For those times when you or a loved one needs help and support for stress and anxiety, </span><a href="https://www.mentalhealth.org.uk/your-mental-health/getting-help" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><b>click here</b></a><span> for links to the Samaritans, Mind and Rethink Mental Health amongst others. </span></p>
<p><span> </span></p>
<h2>Why is Nature Grounding?</h2>
<p><span>In homage to the fact that millions of us turned to the great outdoors during the difficult months of lockdown, the theme of this year’s Mental Health Awareness Week, running from 10-16 May, is nature. </span></p>
<p><span>Without our normal hectic lifestyles, we had more time to go for walks, enjoy green spaces and marvel at the nature all around us. Although the restrictions were tough, being outdoors and connecting with nature had a positive, calming effect. It took our minds off the problems we were facing in other aspects of life. It was mindful, gave us space to think and enabled us to have perspective. </span></p>
<p><b> </b></p>
<h2>10 Grounding Activities to Release Stress</h2>
<p><span>We love the theme of nature so why don’t you join in and try our top nature tips on how to feel more grounded.</span></p>
<p><b> </b></p>
<ol>
<li>
<b></b>
<h3><strong>    Go barefoot</strong></h3>
</li>
</ol>
<p><span>After all, there’s nothing better than the sensory feel of soft grass underfoot to experience childhood innocence, a sense of fun and to lose those inhibitions. </span></p>
<p><b> </b></p>
<ol start="2">
<li>
<b></b>
<h3><strong>    Lay down on the grass</strong></h3>
</li>
</ol>
<p><span>There’s nothing better than lying down with your eyes shut, listening to the sounds of nature and feeling a gentle breeze blow across your face. Take some long, slow breaths or spend a few minutes meditating. It's grounding and life-affirming all at the same time.</span></p>
<p> </p>
<ol start="3">
<li>
<b></b>
<h3><strong>    Listen to nature</strong></h3>
</li>
</ol>
<p><span>One of the simplest pleasures in life is hearing birdsong, a cricket chirping or a stream trickling. Shut your eyes and focus on the sounds, it's like natural hypnosis. And It makes you happy. We don’t know exactly why, but it does.</span></p>
<p><span> </span></p>
<ol start="4">
<li>
<b></b>
<h3><strong>    Paddle in a stream</strong></h3>
</li>
</ol>
<p><span>We used to do it when we were younger, so why did we ever stop? The feel of fresh water can make us giggle with pleasure or wince with pain. It’s refreshing and there’s something about it that cements the connection between humans and the natural world. Water isn’t only just a life-source but it’s a massive component of the human body too. The symbolism isn’t wasted here.  </span></p>
<p><b> </b></p>
<ol start="5">
<li>
<b></b>
<h3><strong>    Have a picnic</strong></h3>
</li>
</ol>
<p><span>Who doesn’t love a picnic in the sunshine? It’s also a great excuse to catch up with  friends and spend time outdoors. If you need that push to get outside, this is a wonderful go-to. Food, socialising and nature’s paradise. Beats sharing a cuppa, grimacing at the carpet that needs a hoover again.</span></p>
<p><b> </b></p>
<ol start="6">
<li>
<b></b>
<h3><strong>    Read a book outside</strong></h3>
</li>
</ol>
<p><span>Really let rip with your imagination and let the great outdoors provide the soundtrack to your next big read. Escapism at its best!</span></p>
<p><b> </b></p>
<ol start="7">
<li>
<b></b>
<h3><strong>    Get into gardening</strong></h3>
</li>
</ol>
<p><span>It’s a truly wonderful hobby and one that leaves you fulfilled. Feel the happy hormones spreading as you nurture young seedlings, bringing joy and hope back into your life. There’s also nothing better for a sense of perspective than watching the cycle of life.</span></p>
<p><b> </b></p>
<ol start="8">
<li>
<b></b>
<h3><strong>    Do an outdoors yoga or exercise class</strong></h3>
</li>
</ol>
<p><span>Why would you go indoors if you can get outside? No more stuffy gyms or sweat laden exercise equipment. Join the millions who prefer a more natural environment for exercise and enjoy the feeling of warm sunshine across your back whilst you Downward Dog. </span></p>
<p><span>If you fancy an outdoor yoga session, try a </span><a href="https://www.yogi-bare.com/collections/yoga-mats/Teddy" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><span>Yogi-Bare Teddy Non-slip Mat</span></a><span>, which has the added benefit that it can be cleaned in a washing machine.</span></p>
<p><span> </span></p>
<ol start="9">
<li>
<b></b>
<h3><strong>    Watch the stars</strong></h3>
</li>
</ol>
<p><span>They’re beautiful and extraordinary and watching them can almost feel like a spiritual experience. What it all means, no-body knows, but the size and age of the universe makes big problems feel inconsequential. That can only be a good thing.</span></p>
<p><b> </b></p>
<ol start="10">
<li>
<h3>
<b></b><span></span>Take a gratitude walk</h3>
</li>
</ol>
<p><span>It might sound wacky but it works. Instead of a nature trail, try a gratitude walk next time and find things that make you smile and feel happy. Perfect for promoting a positive mind-set for the rest of the day. </span></p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.yogi-bare.com/blogs/find-your-y-b/does-an-acupressure-mat-relieve-doms</id>
    <published>2021-05-03T10:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-05-12T05:19:23-05:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.yogi-bare.com/blogs/find-your-y-b/does-an-acupressure-mat-relieve-doms"/>
    <title>Does An Acupressure Mat Relieve DOMS?</title>
    <author>
      <name>James Oakley</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">You might read the title and know exactly what we’re talking about, but for those of you who have no idea what “DOMS” stands for: we’re talking about Delayed Onset Muscle Soreness. In other words, the pain and stiffness that can be felt in your muscles after exercising too heavy or unusual. Since the gyms are open again and we can finally start working out again, we will likely experience DOMS in some way. Whether you have overestimated yourself at the squat rack or you’re experiencing stiffness in your muscles when practicing yoga, pain should never be felt after a good training session. If you are, however, experiencing DOMS after an intense workout, an acupressure mat can help to relieve the pain. In this blog, we will tell you how an acupressure mat works and how it helps to relieve DOMS. </span></p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">How and why do DOMS occur?</span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Delayed Onset Muscle Soreness, also known as DOMS, is a pain or tightness in your muscles that occurs after your workout. Pain that you feel during your workout is different from DOMS and is called Acute Muscle Soreness. DOMS occurs when you’re increasing the intensity of your workout, the frequency of your workouts or if you have a new training schedule. When your muscles have to work harder or in a completely different way, it's believed to cause microscopic damage to the muscle fibres. This might sound insanely scary and dangerous, but we are most likely all familiar with muscle soreness and, naturally, have all lived through it. </span> </p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Since we are getting back into the gyms after a couple of months with less or no physical activity of that intensity, our bodies aren’t used to the strain of workouts anymore. You will likely notice that your first couple of workouts will be harder than usual. Besides that, chances are high you will suffer from DOMS more than before. For one this will result in extreme muscle tightness, whereas others will experience back pain. </span></p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">Acupressure mat to relief DOMS</span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Acupressure has proven to be very effective in </span><a href="https://www.yogi-bare.com/blogs/find-your-y-b/how-does-an-acupressure-mat-work-for-pain-relief" title="Acupressure Pain Relief"><span style="font-weight: 400;">pain relief</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> and can therefore be used to relieve DOMS. After an intense workout, we recommend using an </span><a href="https://www.yogi-bare.com/collections/acupressure/Acupressure-mat" title="Acupressure mat"><span style="font-weight: 400;">acupressure mat</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> for five minutes every day to relax the muscles and aid recovery. Acupressure is an ancient form of massage that finds its origin in Chinese medicine but has increased in popularity over the past years. Nowadays, you can enjoy the benefits of acupressure from the comfort of your own home by using an acupressure mat. This mat contains small plastic spikes that apply pressure to various points of your body. No worries, there is no need to worry about the spikes hurting you, as acupressure is completely painless. By targeting certain nerves and pressure points in your body, acupressure helps to </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">restore balance to the body’s energy flow. </span></p>
<h2>
<span style="font-weight: 400;">Alternative </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">benefits of acupressure </span>
</h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The </span><a href="https://www.yogi-bare.com/blogs/find-your-y-b/10-benefits-of-using-an-acupuncture-mat" title="Benefits of acupressure"><span style="font-weight: 400;">benefits of acupressure</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> don’t stop at pain relief, as it can be used for many other purposes. In fact, a common misconception is that acupressure can only be used to relieve pain and tension in the muscles, whereas it has also proven to be effective in reducing stress and anxiety. Besides that, acupressure can improve your quality of sleep, fight migraines and lower high blood pressures. All in all, a great holistic treatment that can be used for many different health issues. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">If that hasn’t convinced you yet, maybe this will: an acupressure mat has very low costs but very long use. For only $69.95 you don’t only buy a mat, but an entire set including an </span><a href="https://www.yogi-bare.com/collections/acupressure/Acupressure-pillow" title="Acupressure Pillow"><span style="font-weight: 400;">acupressure pillow</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. That’s reason enough to buy one, we would say. </span></p>
<div style="text-align: left;"><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0195/9310/1376/products/Yogi-Bare-Acupressure-pillow-5_480x480.jpg?v=1597830142" alt="Acupressure mat" style="margin-right: 35.5px; margin-left: 35.5px; float: none;"></div>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.yogi-bare.com/blogs/find-your-y-b/debunking-10-acupressure-myths-that-will-put-your-mind-at-ease-before-your-first-session</id>
    <published>2021-04-22T07:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-22T07:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.yogi-bare.com/blogs/find-your-y-b/debunking-10-acupressure-myths-that-will-put-your-mind-at-ease-before-your-first-session"/>
    <title>Debunking 10 Acupressure Myths That Will Put Your Mind At Ease Before Your First Session</title>
    <author>
      <name>James Oakley</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Voluntarily letting someone put tiny needles into your body, it sounds like you’ve lost your mind. However, acupressure has proven to be effective in treating health conditions such as back pain, </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Osteoarthritis and headaches. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Acupressure has been practiced for centuries, in fact, it is believed that acupressure</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> originated around 100 BC in China. In the past decade, acupressure has become increasingly popular in the rest of the world and it is now a well-known treatment option. But still, we often find people stressing over their first acupressure session. That’s why we will be debunking 10 myths that will put your mind at ease.</span></p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">1. Acupressure is extremely painful</span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Chances are high you expect acupressure to be extremely painful. After all, there’s someone sticking needles into your body?! Everyone’s pain levels are different and one might experience pain differently than others, but it’s safe to say that acupressure is painless. After a session, you might feel soreness or bruising at the pressure points but that is nothing to worry about. It’s all part of the process!</span></p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">2. Acupuncture results aren’t instant</span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Another myth is that results of acupuncture aren’t instant and it takes a long time to finally start seeing results. This is not true, you can start experiencing the benefits of acupuncture after the first session already. Depending on the severity of your problem and how your body reacts to the treatment, results can appear quickly. You may even experience immediate relief from a symptom, such as headaches or back pain. In that case; lucky you!</span></p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">3. Acupressure doesn’t work</span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Then there’s the belief that acupressure doesn’t actually work at all, it’s just made up. We can tell you confidently: it definitely works! Give acupressure a chance, go to that first session and experience for yourself. You might feel a bit uncomfortable at first, but once you start experiencing results, you will love it as much as we do. </span></p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">4. It’s part of ancient folklore and nonsense</span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Acupressure is definitely ancient, as it has been around for over 2000 years. However, saying that it’s folklore, nonsense or not legitimate is absolutely not true. Even though acupressure descends from Chinese philosophy, the principles of acupressure are firmly grounded in science.</span></p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">5. Acupuncture conflicts with other medicines</span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">People often believe that acupuncture conflicts with other medicines, but they are very wrong. Acupuncture can be practiced while taking other medication without problem. To elaborate on this, acupuncture is a form of holistic treatment, which is preventative but can also target an existing problem. </span></p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">6. Acupressure is magic and a form of voodoo</span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Some people might think that acupressure is some vague form of magic or voodoo and overall very spiritual. When in fact, acupressure is actually very tangible. While the specifics of how acupressure can heal the human body are unclear, the tiny needles that are used can target pressure points with important nerves. These nerves then send a signal to the brain to release pain relieving hormones. It’s simply science.</span></p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">7. Only pain can be treated with acupressure</span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Next in line, there’s the myth that acupressure can only treat pain. However, acupressure has proven to be effective in treating depression, anxiety, stress, nausea and gynaecological conditions. So no, acupressure is definitely not only for treating pain. </span></p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">8. Acupressure has a lot of side effects</span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">You don’t have to worry about acupressure having acupressure having side effects. After a session, you can easily return to work or continue your day. The only thing you will be experiencing is a positive one: pain relief!</span></p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">9. You can’t just stop with acupressure</span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Once you start acupressure, you will have to continue forever to make the results last. That’s a myth for sure. People with minor pains or issues might benefit from acupressure within only a few sessions, whereas others with bigger issues might need eight to ten sessions to see improvement. However, there’s no need to continue with acupressure once you’re feeling better.</span></p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">10. Acupressure is extremely expensive</span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Finally, let’s talk about money. The price for an acupressure session </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">ranges between </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">$50 and $90. You might only need one or two sessions, but you could need more. What if we tell you that you can practice acupressure with the help of an </span><a href="https://www.yogi-bare.com/collections/acupressure/Acupressure-mat" title="Acupressure mat"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Acupressure Mat</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. The mat works in a similar way as traditional acupressure. You lay down on the mat for ten to twenty minutes and the pressure points made out of plastic will release muscle tension.</span></p>
<div style="text-align: left;"><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0195/9310/1376/products/Yogi-Bare-Acupressure-pillow-5_480x480.jpg?v=1597830142" alt="Acupressure Mat Set" style="margin-right: 35.5px; margin-left: 35.5px; float: none;"></div>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.yogi-bare.com/blogs/find-your-y-b/15-minute-spring-morning-yoga-flow-to-boost-your-energy</id>
    <published>2021-04-19T03:30:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-05-12T05:20:40-05:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.yogi-bare.com/blogs/find-your-y-b/15-minute-spring-morning-yoga-flow-to-boost-your-energy"/>
    <title>15 Minute Spring Morning Yoga Flow To Boost Your Energy</title>
    <author>
      <name>James Oakley</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">After the much-maligned darkness of winter, there’s nothing more heart-warming than the warmth of sunshine radiating down on us, nourishing us with essential Vitamin D and boosting our psychological health. And there’s no better way to bounce into spring than with an exhilarating morning yoga session.  </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"> </span></p>
<h2>Energy Boosting Yoga Routine</h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">A round of sun salutations is the classic energising quick morning yoga flow that awakens the body, stimulating the circulatory and digestive systems, and easing overnight stiffness.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Follow on with some strengthening Warrior poses and complete your morning ritual, if you dare,  with the king of all yoga poses, the headstand. It’s an invigorating routine to get the juices flowing and set you up for the rest of the day.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"> </span></p>
<h2>Morning Yoga Routine</h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Wherever you plan to do your morning yoga routine, make sure you’re using a non-slip yoga mat. An essential for every yogi, these prevent slipping and sliding, absorb moisture from sweaty palms and feet and support joints, balance and posture.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">For indoors, try our<span> </span></span><a href="https://www.yogi-bare.com/collections/yoga-mats/Paws" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><b>Yogi-Bare Paws Non-slip Mat</b></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"><span> </span>for extreme grip technology. If you fancy taking your practise outdoors now the weather’s balmier, opt for our lightweight, perfectly portable<span> </span></span><a href="https://www.yogi-bare.com/collections/yoga-mats/Teddy" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><b>Yogi Bare Teddy Mat</b></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. Available in funky designs like tropical, cosmic or nevada, these mats will stimulate your senses as much as nature’s paradise does.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"> </span></p>
<h2>15 Minutes of Yoga</h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Begin our perfect spring to summer yoga routine in Mountain Pose.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"> </span></p>
<h3>Flat Back (Ardha Uttanasana)</h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">On the next exhale, bend forwards, bringing your arms down. Lay your palms flat on the floor so they’re in line with the toes. You can bend your knees a little if you prefer. Inhale, lift your head, keep it in line with your back which should be flat horizontally. Rest hands on the thighs or let your fingertips brush the floor.</span></p>
<p> </p>
<h3>Plank </h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">As you exhale, plant your palms firmly onto the floor. Step or jump legs back into the plank position. Shoulders should align over your wrists. The idea is to aim for a straight line from the crown of your head to your heels. Arms stay strong, pushing into the ground. </span></p>
<p> </p>
<h3>Knees, Chest and Chin (Chaturanga Dandasana)</h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Exhale. Lower your knees, chest and chin until they touch the floor. Keep elbows tucked in as you do so, bottom and hips should remain held high. Shoulders should be positioned right over the hands. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> </span></p>
<br>
<h3>Cobra (Bhujangasana)</h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Inhale. Bring head and chest up, reaching forwards. Lower your bottom and knees until your legs are  flat along the floor. Elbows move backwards, pointing towards the hips. You should feel a slight backbend. Anchor hips and feet to the floor. </span></p>
<p> </p>
<h3>Downward Facing Dog (Adho Mukha Svanasana)</h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Exhale. Push back into downward facing dog. Come through hands and knees if necessary. Press fingertips lightly onto the floor. Your back and legs invert to create a triangle shape. </span></p>
<p> </p>
<h3>Forward Bend (Uttanasana)</h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Exhale. Step the right foot forward, bringing it next to your right hand. Bring the left foot forward to join it. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Come back into Mountain Pose to finish your first sun salutation routine. Repeat a minimum of 2-3 rounds. </span></p>
<p> </p>
<h3>Warrior I (Virabhadrasana)<span style="font-weight: 400;"> </span>
</h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">When you’re ready, move on to Warrior I to build strength and stamina.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Lift your right leg forwards, bending into the right thigh. Root left foot to the spot, heel on the floor but turned at a 45° angle. Arms reach up overhead, fingertips point towards the sky and draw the stomach in. If you like, you can also go into Warrior 2 and Warrior 3 from here. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"> </span></p>
<h3>Dolphin Pose (Ardha Pincha Mayurasana)</h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Begin on hands and knees, forearms should be shoulder-width apart. Elbows remain in place, clasp hands and lift hips up high. Lower head and remain in pose for at least 5 deep breaths.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">  </span></p>
<h3>Half Headstand/Headstand (Shirshasana)</h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Okay so not everyone feels quite up to a headstand understandably so don’t panic. If you’d rather not, just replace the headstand with your choice of seated poses instead. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Don’t try this pose if you’ve currently got a neck or back injury. If you’ve had one of any severity in the past, you may also want to leave this out altogether or take advice from your doctor or yoga teacher. Headstand, in some cases, can make injuries worse.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">It’s also not recommended if you have hypertension or glaucoma, which can be aggravated by the headstand. A headstand can worsen your symptoms if you suffer arthritis. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Yoga blocks under the forearms are a great idea to take pressure off the head in this pose.<span> </span></span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Try our<span> </span></span><a href="https://www.yogi-bare.com/collections/props-blocks-straps/Block" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><span style="font-weight: 400;">firm foam support block</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"><span> </span>or our<span> </span></span><a href="https://www.yogi-bare.com/collections/props-blocks-straps/products/yoga-block-bamboo-bamboo-support-block" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><span style="font-weight: 400;">bamboo support block</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"><span> </span>for extra support.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Keep feet in as close to the elbows as possible. Slowly, take them one at a time, lift each heel up to the buttocks, forming an egg shape. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">From half-headstand, begin by reaching feet straight up over shoulders and hips when you feel stable enough to do so. Lengthen your legs, flexing or pointing toes. Keep shoulders away from the head to protect the neck from being compressed too much.</span></p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.yogi-bare.com/blogs/find-your-y-b/how-to-embrace-outdoor-yoga-this-spring</id>
    <published>2021-04-12T02:30:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-23T10:18:00-05:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.yogi-bare.com/blogs/find-your-y-b/how-to-embrace-outdoor-yoga-this-spring"/>
    <title>How To Embrace Outdoor Yoga This Summer 2021</title>
    <author>
      <name>James Oakley</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">After months and months of being, quite literally, locked away in our houses, we finally have the freedom to spend time both outdoors and indoors</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Whereas the daily walk was the highlight of our days before, we can now meet up with friends and family in the garden, park or on the beach. With Summer coming in quickly, it’s getting warmer and nicer outside every single day, fueling our urge to go outside even more. After lockdown, where you might have spent months practicing yoga in the same environment every single day, we imagine you may want to spend a bit of time practicing your moves outside. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Grab your yoga mat and join us on practicing outdoor yoga this Summer. What are you waiting for? If you need a bit more motivation, we will guide you through how you can embrace outdoor yoga in this blog.</span></p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">Bring your friends to the park</span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The best part about practicing yoga outdoors is that you can assemble a couple of friends to join, as long as social distancing is complied. If you have a park in the neighborhood, you will only need a yoga mat and good company to get started. Or if you prefer a quiet moment for yourself, that’s all up to you. As you will be transporting your yoga mat, it’s convenient to use a </span><a href="https://www.yogi-bare.com/collections/props-blocks-straps/Carry-strap" title="Yoga mat carry strap"><span style="font-weight: 400;">carry strap</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> to make your life a bit easier. Find a quiet place in the park, lay out your yoga mats and begin your yoga flow. Don’t forget to inhale deep breaths of fresh air, after all, you should fully enjoy the outdoors!</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0195/9310/1376/files/Yogi-Bare-Paws-X-Yoga-Mat-8_1296_480x480.jpg?v=1615206686" alt="Yoga mat carry strap" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"></span></p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">Use a lightweight yoga mat</span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">If you’re planning to fully enjoy your freedom and do all your yoga practices outdoors, we recommend opting for a </span><a href="https://www.yogi-bare.com/collections/yoga-mats/Best-for_Travel" title="Travel yoga mat"><span style="font-weight: 400;">travel yoga mat</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. Since you will be carrying it around quite a bit, it won’t hurt if the yoga mat is lightweight and easy to transport. Besides its weight, you should also make sure the yoga mat is easy to clean, as you will be practicing outside and the mat might get dirtier than usual. Thankfully, the yoga mats by Yogi Bare can all be cleaned easily by simply using some warm water with fresh lemon juice. This helps to get rid of built up oils on your yoga mat. Cleaning your yoga mat on a regular basis, preferably weekly, is important to make it last a long time. </span></p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">Bring all your workout essentials</span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Now that we’re almost ready to go, don’t forget to bring your workout essentials. Always bring a big bottle of water to keep you hydrated throughout the yoga practice and if you prefer, you can take along a box to play some music on as well. If you’re working out by yourself, you might prefer using earphones to be completely absorbed in the moment. Put on a calming yoga playlist on Spotify and enjoy the feeling of moving your body to the sound of the music. Music can actually help to find rhythm in your yoga flow and helps you to move smoother. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0195/9310/1376/files/music-yoga_480x480.jpg?v=1617951889" alt="Music during yoga practice" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"></span></p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">Pick a quiet time of day </span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Depending on your preferences, you might want to skip the busiest time of day</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. A yoga practice should be all about finding your calm, winding down and taking a moment for yourself. This might be a bit difficult if half of your city or town is walking by or your kid’s neighbours end up running over your yoga mat. Early in the morning is often a perfect time to practice yoga outdoors, if the temperature allows it. You might want to start off with an extra layer on! On a sunny day, don’t think too long about it, but simply grab your yoga mat and enjoy soaking up some </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">vitamin D</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> while you exercise. </span></p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.yogi-bare.com/blogs/find-your-y-b/5-easy-to-master-acro-yoga-poses-to-spice-up-your-everyday-flow</id>
    <published>2021-04-09T11:30:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-14T11:21:09-05:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.yogi-bare.com/blogs/find-your-y-b/5-easy-to-master-acro-yoga-poses-to-spice-up-your-everyday-flow"/>
    <title>5 Easy To Master Acro Yoga Poses To Spice Up Your Everyday Flow</title>
    <author>
      <name>James Oakley</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p><span>You’ve probably put two and two together already by now and guessed that Acro Yoga combines yoga with acrobatics. Okay, it may not be the most original title, but It’s definitely not your average yoga practise. Why? Because after the solo warm-up, you move on to partner-work creating dynamic lift poses. Think contemporary dance meets acrobatics when it comes to this yoga fusion. Pretty cool right?</span></p>
<p><span> </span></p>
<h2>Benefits of Acro Yoga</h2>
<p><span>Emanating mainly from the USA, this discipline, full of grace and poise, was brought into our consciousness by a dancer and yogi after realising similarities in breathwork and physical awareness. It’s a fantastically powerful, physically demanding form of yoga that builds strength and balance from the core, legs and arms in both the flyer (the person being lifted) and the base (the person doing the lifting). Inversions, including headstands and handstands play a big part too which stimulates blood circulation. After a session, you’re left feeling energised, full of positivity and more than likely, wild dreams of joining the circus. </span></p>
<p><span>Acro Yoga is hugely beneficial for mental health too. Whilst some poses may be more challenging; the sense of achievement from them builds confidence and empowerment. Trust is obviously paramount between partners and a strong emotional connection and warmness is built whilst working in partnership. There’s even an element of therapeutic Thai massage in some of the poses! It really is a yoga style unlike any other you’ve seen. </span></p>
<p><span> </span></p>
<h2>Should I Use a Yoga Mat?</h2>
<p><span>Having something soft and grippy for floorwork is essential. For Acro Yoga, </span><span>we’d recommend our </span><a href="https://www.yogi-bare.com/collections/yoga-mats/paws" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><b>Yogi-Bare Paws X Non-slip Mat</b></a><b>.</b><span> This mat is wider than normal, exactly what you need when there’s two of you. It also uses advanced grip technology so even if you do get a sweat on, it's unlikely you’ll fall out of pose </span></p>
<p><span> </span></p>
<h2>Beginners Guide to Acro Yoga</h2>
<p><span>Don’t get put off by the fact that you’re a newbie. With guidance, anyone can do these poses but that said, attending a class to begin with is a good idea. An experienced instructor will certainly give you the basics and ensure safe practise. </span></p>
<p><span>Begin by agreeing the roles of base and flyer with your partner. The general rule of thumb is that the larger person takes on the role of base. Ideally, you should also have a spotter (another person) on hand, ready to adjust the pose and catch the flyer if anyone wobbles or falls.</span></p>
<p><span>Constant communication is the key to success with Acro Yoga. You all need to know the intentions for the pose, how one another is feeling and if anyone wants to stop at any time.</span></p>
<p><span> </span></p>
<h2>5 Easy to Master Acro Yoga Poses</h2>
<h3>Base Test 1</h3>
<p><b> </b></p>
<p><span>A nice pose to ease into your routine, this also helps the base learn stability.</span></p>
<p><span>Base lies down on their back. Legs are vertical, with feet stacked over hips. If you’re much taller than your flyer, you can bend your knees, otherwise they may find it difficult to reach.</span></p>
<p><span>Flyer crosses their forearms, rests them onto the base's feet, pressing down. Hold for a few breaths. </span></p>
<p><span> </span></p>
<h3>Base Test 2</h3>
<p><span>If you’d like to strengthen Base test 1, the flyer lifts legs off the ground. </span></p>
<p><span>Once you both feel stable, base can straighten legs either at a 90® angle or into an L-shape. Stack feet over hips to remain stable. When you’re ready to come out of pose, lower the flyer gently back down.</span></p>
<p><span> </span></p>
<h3>Plank Press</h3>
<p><span>Base lies down on their back and rests their feet onto the flyer’s hips, keeping them parallel and hip-width apart, with knees bent.</span></p>
<p><span>Flyer stands at the base’s feet. Stretch arms out to the side in a T-shape. Keep your body firm and engage the abdominals.</span></p>
<p><span>The base can now bend their knees more. Taking it slowly, start to receive more of the flyer’s body weight. Lower the flyer down gently by a few inches and then back into standing. With this one, it’s important that the flyer keeps their feet on the ground and trusts their weight to the base, who is effectively holding them in place.</span></p>
<p><span> </span></p>
<h3>Plank on Plank</h3>
<p><span>Spice up this classic yoga pose with a partner. </span></p>
<p><span>Base gets into position first, adopting the plank pose. A strong plank means hands are shoulder-width apart, core is pulled in, whilst arms are kept straight.</span></p>
<p><span>Flyer faces the base’s feet, then places hands on the base’s ankles. Now, press down onto the ankles with straightened arms. Carefully lift the foot closest to the base. Place your ankle on the shoulder furthest away. Toes should stay pointed, pressing into the top of that foot. Engage your leg and core muscles, bringing strength and balance to the pose. Slowly place your second foot on the base’s near shoulder. Align your shoulders over the base’s ankles for stability.</span></p>
<p><span> </span></p>
<h3>Folder Leaf</h3>
<p><span>A great introduction to the more therapeutic Acro Yoga poses.</span></p>
<p><span>Base lies on their back, placing their feet on the groin of the flyer. Keep feet turned out slightly.</span></p>
<p><span>Flyer leans forward, lifting legs up whilst holding the hands of the base. As the flyer is doing this, base bends their legs initially, then lifts the flyer upwards in a more controlled manner. From the front plank, flyer lets go of the base’s hands and bends downwards, arms hanging down alongside the base’s legs. </span></p>
<p><span>To come out of pose, base gently manoeuvres flyer back into the front plank, then gently lower them back down again into standing position.</span></p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.yogi-bare.com/blogs/find-your-y-b/build-your-home-yoga-studio-ready-for-summer-2021</id>
    <published>2021-04-06T03:33:04-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-23T10:49:20-05:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.yogi-bare.com/blogs/find-your-y-b/build-your-home-yoga-studio-ready-for-summer-2021"/>
    <title>Build Your Home Yoga Studio For Summer 2021</title>
    <author>
      <name>James Oakley</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">With people spending more time at home, it is important to create peace and tranquillity in the spaces that we spend most of our time in. It doesn't matter the amount of space that you have, balance can be achieved in even the smallest of homes. In 2021, your yoga session might look and feel a bit different than it used to be, </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">yoga classes have reopened, but many are now comfortable practising in their own homes, away from the hustle and bustle.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">It’s important to remember that the spaces we practice our yoga in complements our technique.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> You might have noticed when you attend your usual yoga class that the space you practice in is very minimalistic and full of natural light. This is what you want to achieve in your home yoga studio to get the most out of your personal or online yoga session. Read on to learn how Yogi Bare can help you achieve your own home yoga studio with ease.</span></p>
<p> </p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">Choosing The Right Space For Your Home Yoga Studio</span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Firstly, the space you choose to practice your yoga in is important to how much fulfilment you gain from a home yoga session. To have a clear mind, you need to remove any clutter that is surrounding your home yoga studio. Clutter prevents you from focusing on your breathing, therefore disrupting your inner chi. Unnecessary clutter in your home yoga studio causes stress, which might cloud your mind when focussing on your yoga technique. Another important factor to consider when creating your home yoga studio is where in your home are you going to locate your studio. If you are fortunate enough to have a green space, such as a garden this can be the ideal place to practice yoga. Being mindful of nature and having access to flowing air when you practice your yoga technique can be key to achieving spiritual fulfilment. A good idea is to convert an unused shed into a home yoga studio, which can be dedicated to your practice and where you can detach yourself from the everyday. Yogi Bare knows not everyone has access to a garden, so you need to ensure that your home yoga studio is situated somewhere in your home where you can use your yoga mat, but also quiet enough so you can meditate.</span></p>
<p> </p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-weight: 400;"><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0195/9310/1376/files/2_1800x709_755af12a-6146-4761-8748-2d5d280f93bf_480x480.jpg?v=1553164862" alt=""></span></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"> </p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">Choosing The Right Light For Your Home Yoga Studio</span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Lighting is important to our zen when practising yoga, because it allows us to free ourselves from stress and to create a harmonious environment to practice our technique. Light allows us to achieve balance which can be severely affected by a sharp or blurry light. The best light you can have for your home yoga studio is natural light. The light from the sun is a great source of vitamins but also improves our overall happiness. It will allow your yoga session to be connected with nature and it will give you the energy to practice even more. However, we can’t all rely on natural sunlight to light our yoga home studio. So it's important that you choose soft hues and warm lights to replicate the healing properties of the sun. </span> </p>
<p> </p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">Choosing The Right Environment For Your Home Yoga Studio</span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Yogi Bare believes that if you are designing a home yoga studio, it's important to remember what you put in your studio can affect your workout. So instead of filling your studio with the latest technology, which will only distract you from achieving fulfilment from your yoga practice, it is important to surround yourself with only the essentials of yoga such as your mat and crystals. Floor space is key to being able to stay focussed and gives you the ability to move freely. If you decide to add to your yoga home studio, Yogi Bare suggests you surround yourself with house plants that will add oxygen to your room but also allow you to reconnect with the earth. This will help you to achieve a natural equilibrium, </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">enhancing your yoga experience.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"> If you need more help with creating your home yoga studio, why not check out our build your own home yoga studio kit.</span><br><br></p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.yogi-bare.com/blogs/find-your-y-b/yoga-hygiene-returning-to-the-studio</id>
    <published>2021-03-30T03:42:55-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-23T10:26:33-05:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.yogi-bare.com/blogs/find-your-y-b/yoga-hygiene-returning-to-the-studio"/>
    <title>Yoga Hygiene - Returning to the Studio</title>
    <author>
      <name>James Oakley</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Lockdown restrictions are finally lifting but the psychological scars of the pandemic will last for years to come. So, with the reopening of yoga studios, gyms and group exercise in sight, the best thing we can do for our mental and physical health is to go back to them. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Whilst the vaccine roll out is steaming ahead, and many of us are eager to work out, hygiene is paramount whilst COVID-19 remains in the community.</span></p>
<p> </p>
<h2><span>Yoga Hygiene</span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Exercising in the comfort of your own space is obviously the safest and most hygienic option</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. It’s lucky that yoga is easy to do at home with little equipment. It’s not as practical to have a home gym nor as much fun doing a zoom Zumba class though. Also, group exercise of any form offers many social and psychological benefits, as well as being fantastically motivating. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The simple truth is that sharing mats allows germs to be passed on, especially Plantar Warts, Athlete’s Foot, Cold and Flu as well as COVID-19. If you have done so, or are planning on returning to the studio or any group exercise class for that matter, stay safe and prevent the spread of COVID-19 by</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> bringing your own mat. Other must-haves for your gym bag are hand sanitiser, antibacterial wipes, hand or head towel and of course your own bottle of water. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">All yoga studios or gyms should take the risk of </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">COVID-19</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> seriously and do everything possible to mitigate risk. If in doubt, ask them about their protocols. Good indicators include:</span></p>
<p> </p>
<ul>
<li><span>      A spacious studio</span></li>
<li><span>      Pre-booked classes only</span></li>
<li><span>      Hand sanitiser on arrival</span></li>
<li><span>      Fewer people in class</span></li>
<li><span>      Attendees to bring their own mat</span></li>
<li><span>      Social distancing in operation</span></li>
<li><span>      Staggered arrival between classes</span></li>
<li><span>      Sanitising procedures after each class</span></li>
<li><span>      Doors or windows open for ventilation</span></li>
<li><span>      Hand sanitizers and antibacterial wipes in the toilet</span></li>
<li><span>      Health and safety training for staff</span></li>
</ul>
<p><span> </span></p>
<p><span><span style="font-weight: 400;">The UK’s vaccination program has been nothing short of epic. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">As it stands at the time of writing, 74.6 million doses of the vaccine have been given.</span> That said, we all still have a personal responsibility in reducing transmission. If you have any symptoms of Covid-19 or have been a close contact of someone who has tested positive, do the right thing and stay away from your class. </span></p>
<p><span> </span></p>
<h2><span>Yogi Bare Teddy Mats</span></h2>
<p><span>If you’re wondering what yoga mat to get, we’ve got the answer. Created by a trailblazing, eco-friendly, and practical yogi, the </span><a href="https://www.yogi-bare.com/collections/yoga-mats/Teddy" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><b>Teddy Mat</b></a><span> </span><span>is </span><i><span>the</span></i><span> ultimate, portable high-performance non-slip yoga mat. It's ideal for using outdoors, on holiday or bringing to a group class. Even better, this foldable travel mat is extremely versatile. Use it for traditional yoga, hot yoga, the gym, calisthenics, stretching, Pilates, or any other exercise class. At 1.5kg, it’s so lightweight and folds up into a small square making it really easy to transport.</span></p>
<p><span>Let’s talk some more about the superb grip this mat gives. The velvet microfiber surface becomes grippy under sweat and moisture, whilst the natural sustainable rubber base grips to the floor, preventing bunching up. The Teddy Mat also supports the impact on ankles, wrists and knees and prevents slipping and sliding, the cause of many injuries. Don’t mind us if we say they look pretty funky too. Attractively designed, you can choose from Tropical, Cosmic or Nevada.</span></p>
<p><span> </span></p>
<h2><span>How to Clean Your Yoga Mat</span></h2>
<p><span>Yoga mats that are used outdoors, in a hot room, a sweaty gym or at different venues tend to pick up grime, sweat and germs. Luckily, it’s so easy to keep your Teddy Mat clean. Put it on a quick wash in the washing machine at 30/40 degrees with a small amount of detergent. After that, hang it up to dry and store out of direct sunlight. Job done!</span></p>
<p><span> </span></p>
<h2><span>Yoga Carry Straps</span></h2>
<p><span>A carry strap is a great way to transport your yoga mat from home to studio with-out hassle. Give your mat a hug with a </span><a href="https://www.yogi-bare.com/collections/props-blocks-straps/Carry-strap" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><b>Yogi Bare Carrying Strap</b></a><span>. These are beautifully designed, stylish and of course, functional. Simply wrap around both ends of your rolled yoga mat, creating a shoulder strap.</span></p>
<p><span>The incredible strength of these straps is all down to the fact that these are crafted from vegan leather and durable, strong nylon webbing. Fully adjustable, they snugly fit any yoga mat at the length and height you find most comfortable. Keep your removable strap clean with a quick wipe down. </span></p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.yogi-bare.com/blogs/find-your-y-b/5-ways-to-use-a-yoga-wheel-for-back-pain</id>
    <published>2021-03-22T05:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-22T05:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.yogi-bare.com/blogs/find-your-y-b/5-ways-to-use-a-yoga-wheel-for-back-pain"/>
    <title>5 Ways To Use A Yoga Wheel For Back Pain</title>
    <author>
      <name>James Oakley</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">It’s a well-known fact that practicing yoga regularly can help to prevent or relieve back pain. There are, however, attributes that can be used during yoga practice to deepen your stretches and to reduce back pain even more. Chances are high you’ve heard of a </span><a href="https://www.yogi-bare.com/collections/props-blocks-straps/Strap" title="Yoga stretch strap"><span style="font-weight: 400;">yoga stretch strap</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> and a </span><a href="https://www.yogi-bare.com/collections/props-blocks-straps/Block" title="Yoga block"><span style="font-weight: 400;">yoga block</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> before, but are you familiar with a yoga wheel yet? If not, we are here to introduce you to one of the best attributes to use during yoga to alleviate back pain.</span></p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">What is a yoga wheel? </span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">A </span><a href="https://www.yogi-bare.com/collections/props-blocks-straps/Wheel" title="Yoga wheel"><span style="font-weight: 400;">yoga wheel</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> is a hollow, circular-shaped attribute for yogis that can be used during yoga practice to help with stretches, improve your flexibility and release upper and lower back pain. With a 13cm width and a thickness of 1.6cm, the yoga wheel has the perfect size and shape to support your body while practicing yoga. The yoga wheel is made out of strong material which makes it no problem to rest your entire body weight onto the yoga accessory. </span></p>
<p><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0195/9310/1376/files/Yogi-Bare-PRODUCT-COLOUR-10_1296x_Cropped_25f0a487-91f3-4c39-9871-3e473c5f805c_480x480.jpg?v=1616136430" alt="" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;" width="300" height="300"></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The relatively new accessory was introduced into the yoga world in 2014 and has increased in popularity ever since. The best thing about the yoga wheel is that it doesn’t serve one single purpose but instead, it helps you with different challenges. Therefore, you can decide for yourself what it is you want to use a yoga wheel for. Whether your challenge is flexibility, strength or you’re struggling with aches and pains; the yoga wheel can be the solution. </span></p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">How to use a yoga wheel </span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The yoga wheel can be used for multiple purposes and each way requires a different approach. You can use the yoga wheel for a wonderful massage to warm up your muscles before getting started with your yoga flow. Start off with stretching your upper body by placing your hands on the yoga wheel while kneeling. Press your shoulders down and you will feel a great stretch through your shoulders, arms, chest and core. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">If you want to stretch your upper and lower back, place the yoga wheel below your back and slowly move back and forth to make sure the yoga wheel targets your entire back. This will not only warm up your muscles but can relieve pain as well. If you’re interested in the ins and outs of </span><a href="https://www.yogi-bare.com/blogs/find-your-y-b/do-yoga-wheels-help-back-pain" title="Yoga wheels for back pain"><span style="font-weight: 400;">yoga wheels for back pain</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, you can read about them in our blog. </span> </p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">You might want to stretch your legs, especially if you’re already sore from previous practice. The yoga wheel intensifies the stretch if you place your feet on top of it while you’re sitting down. You will feel a deep, intense stretch through your hamstrings, glutes and calves. </span></p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">Best yoga wheel exercises for your back</span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Are you interested in reading about relaxing full body exercises you can do with a yoga wheel, then we would like to refer you to our blog about </span><a href="https://www.yogi-bare.co.uk/blogs/news/5-zen-poses-using-a-yoga-wheel" title="Zen poses with yoga wheel"><span style="font-weight: 400;">5 zen yoga poses using a yoga wheel</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. However, if you’re struggling with back pain and you’re interested in hearing about the best yoga wheel exercises that focus on your back, you’re in the right place. </span></p>
<p><strong>1. Child’s pose</strong></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">An exercise that is incorporated into almost every yoga practice is the child’s pose and thankfully, there’s a way to do this pose while using the yoga wheel. Place the yoga wheel in front of you, sit down on your knees and grab the wheel with your hands. Roll the wheel forward to get a stretch throughout your upper back. </span></p>
<p><strong>2. Easy pose</strong></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">As the name suggests, this pose is relatively easy and can be done by everyone, even if you’re a beginner yogi. For this exercise, you’ll want to sit in front of your yoga wheel while sitting crossed-legged. Lean against the yoga wheel and slowly extend your spine over the top of the wheel. A great exercise to release tension between your shoulders and in your upper back.</span></p>
<p><strong>3. Fish pose</strong></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">We are slowly increasing the difficulty of the exercises by moving into the wheel-assisted fish pose, where you lay on top of the yoga wheel with your legs extended. Make sure the yoga wheel is aligned with your back and parallel to your spine. Lean backward and enjoy the stretch you will feel in your lower and upper back.</span></p>
<p><strong>4. Reclining hero pose</strong></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Next, kneel down with your knees hip-distance apart, sit down on your feet and place the yoga wheel behind you. Roll your spine onto the wheel and stretch your arms beyond your head, which will give you an intense stretch throughout your quads, back and shoulders. </span></p>
<p><strong>5. Open shoulders extended pose</strong></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Then finally, our last pose will not only stretch our back but the shoulders as well. The open shoulders extended stretch is performed by laying on your stomach with the yoga wheel placed below your hips. Move your legs up and keep your upper body as close to the ground as possible. You will feel this stretch in your entire back as well as your core and shoulders. </span></p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.yogi-bare.com/blogs/find-your-y-b/6-yoga-poses-to-help-you-welcome-in-spring</id>
    <published>2021-03-19T05:56:04-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-23T10:59:42-05:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.yogi-bare.com/blogs/find-your-y-b/6-yoga-poses-to-help-you-welcome-in-spring"/>
    <title>6 Yoga Poses To Help You Welcome In Summer 2021</title>
    <author>
      <name>James Oakley</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">After what feels like forever in a lockdown, there are burgeoning signs that Summer 2021 has arrived. Longer days, milder weather and trips to the beach can only come as a welcome relief. Hello sunshine and goodbye frost. The world is quite literally bursting awake from its lockdown hibernation with a renewed sense of joy and vitality. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The season of summer brings with it a natural inclination to cleanse and detoxify. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Capitalise on this season’s growth mindset</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> and adopt a revitalising yoga routine to rebalance body and mind.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"> </span></p>
<h2>Get Prepared</h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Slipping and sliding can be dangerous and is a common cause of injury. When doing yoga, it's essential to use a non-slip yoga mat. This will also support joints, balance and posture and there’s much less likelihood of injury. For indoors,<span> </span></span><span style="font-weight: 400;">we’d recommend trying our high performance<span> </span></span><a href="https://www.yogi-bare.com/collections/yoga-mats/products/yogi-bare-paws-natural-rubber-extreme-grip-yoga-mat-black" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Yogi-Bare Paws Non-slip Mat</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"><span> </span>for extreme grip technology. If you fancy an outdoor yoga session, try a<span> </span></span><a href="https://www.yogi-bare.com/collections/yoga-mats/Teddy" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Yogi-Bare Teddy Non-slip Mat</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, which has the added benefit that it can be cleaned in a washing machine.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"> </span></p>
<h2>6 Yoga Poses to Help You Welcome In Summer</h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">You can warm up with some sun salutations or a few rounds of cat-cow to loosen muscles.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"> </span></p>
<h3>Fierce Pose (Utkatasana)</h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Begin your routine by strengthening and lengthening the body with this pose, otherwise known as the chair pose too.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Start with your feet together. Bend your knees and lower your hips towards the floor as if sitting down into a chair. Reach arms upwards towards the sky. Hold the pose and feel strong, fierce and powerful.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"> </span></p>
<h3>Divers Pose (Drinking Bird Pose)</h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Use this pose to stretch the entire lower body.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Straighten your legs before you do anything further. The key to this one is that you need to hinge (or lean) forward from your hips until your upper body is parallel with the floor. Once you’ve done this, it’s time to incorporate an oppositional stretch. Reach your arms backwards whilst sending the crown of your head forwards. Lift your heels up so that you’re on tiptoes.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"> </span></p>
<h3>Crescent High Lunge (Ashta Chandrasana)</h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This is a fantastic pose for opening up the hip and groin area and is also known to be good for indigestion. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Step the left foot towards the back of your mat. Bend your front knee, so that it’s sitting directly over your ankle. Stay on the ball of your back foot and gently straighten your back leg. Reach up with both arms, keeping your gaze forward. From here, you can either go straight into Warrior I or if you fancy a back stretch, move into a high lunge backbend and then a low lunge backbend.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"> </span></p>
<h3>Warrior I (Virabhadrasana)</h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">An energising stretch for the whole body, this is<span> </span></span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">the</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"><span> </span>pose to build focus, power and stability.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Lift your right leg forwards, bending into the right thigh. Left foot stays in place, with the heel on the floor and turned at a 45° angle. Reach up arms overhead, fingertips towards the sky and draw the stomach in. </span></p>
<p> </p>
<h3>Downward Facing Dog (Adho Mukha Svanasana)</h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The classic yoga pose that strengthens the core, improves circulation and provides a wonderful full body stretch.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">From Warrior 1, lower your arms down. Exhale. Step back into plank position before pushing-up into cobra. Fingertips press lightly on the floor. From cobra, tuck your toes under, press into your hands to lift your body up and push back into downward facing dog. This is where the spine and legs invert to create a triangle shape, keeping the back of legs and spine lengthened. Hips are lifted up, elbows soft, heels drop towards the floor and you should also feel a nice stretch across the chest.</span></p>
<br>
<h3>Half Moon Pose (Ardha Chandrasana)</h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This gives a great stretch through two opposing movements. Being rooted to the spot symbolises the calm, balancing energy of the moon, whilst the stretch upwards embodies the fierce, fiery force of the sun. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Place your right hand on the floor in front of your right foot. Carefully lift your left leg, keeping your left hip open and flex your left foot. Stretch your left arm skywards. When you feel balanced, look upwards.</span></p>
<br>
<h3>Final Poses</h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">You could finish your sequence with any number of stretches. We especially like to finish off with the camel pose, boat pose, plow pose and finally, the child’s pose </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">- before you know it you’ll feel fresh as a daisy, ready to enjoy the summer sun.</span></p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.yogi-bare.com/blogs/find-your-y-b/what-is-bikram-yoga</id>
    <published>2021-03-16T11:54:27-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-16T11:54:27-05:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.yogi-bare.com/blogs/find-your-y-b/what-is-bikram-yoga"/>
    <title>What is Bikram Yoga?</title>
    <author>
      <name>James Oakley</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Although it’s become more prominent in recent years, you might be surprised to hear that Bikram yoga was originally practised during the early 1970s. ‘Hot yoga’ as it's often called, was devised by Bikram Choudhury when he began to experiment with using heaters in his yoga room. It was quickly adopted by the Hollywood elite, one of them being a certain Shirley MacLaine. Since then, its continued to grow in popularity although the practise has distanced itself from its creator after sexual abuse allegations later surfaced.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"> </span></p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">What is Bikram Yoga?</span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The practice of Bikram yoga consists of a sequence of 26 asanas (poses) that are practised in an artificially heated room, the temperature set to 105°F (41° C) with a humidity of 40%. Hot rooms are normally covered in carpets and fitted with mirrors, to replicate the climate of India, the birthplace and spiritual centre of yoga. It’s a noticeable heat, a little like walking into a sauna. Once you get going and begin to sweat, your body adjusts to the temperature and you notice it less. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"> </span></p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Benefits of Bikram Yoga</span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">So why the heat? When you start to think about it, sweating for health benefits is central to many cultures. Think of Turkish baths, Moroccan hammam and Finnish saunas.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Certainly, heat encourages the body to sweat out toxins and burn more calories. That in itself is enough for some. Another significant health benefit is that when you exercise in a hot environment, it also strengthens the cardiovascular system, because it makes the heartbeat faster.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The warmth also allows the muscles to stretch further and ligaments to relax. You gain a greater range of motion which makes it easier to get into poses.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Yoga is of course, famed for its mental health benefits too. Those that practise it regularly report less depression, anxiety and stress. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"> </span></p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">What to Wear for Bikram Yoga</span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">You’re going to get hot. Very hot. So, the key is not to over dress. Bulky, uncomfortable clothing and long leggings are likely to make you overheat, stick to your skin, distract you from breathing properly and from focusing on the correct posture and alignment. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Instead use light, thin and breathable materials. You want something that feels comfortable and is fully movable that you can stretch in. Most exercise- specific clothing will be made of suitable materials. Long hair clinging to your neck and back is a pretty unpleasant sensation so keep it tied up for this form of yoga. </span></p>
<br>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">For more, you can read our blog ‘</span><a href="https://www.yogi-bare.com/blogs/news/what-to-wear-to-a-hot-yoga-class" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><span style="font-weight: 400;">What To Wear To Hot Yoga Class</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">’.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"> </span></p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">Bikram Yoga: The Essentials</span></h2>
<h3><span style="font-weight: 400;">H20</span></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">There’s no doubt that a Bikram Yoga session will leave you feeling seriously thirsty. Try to come to the class fully hydrated. It’s imperative to rehydrate and replenish lost water as you sweat out large quantities. Without proper hydration, you run the risk of a nasty headache. Do bring a bottle of water with you and take sips throughout the rest of the day. </span></p>
<br>
<h3><span style="font-weight: 400;">Common-sense</span></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Don’t push yourself too far, especially if you’re a beginner. Bring a healthy dose of common sense with you and if you need to sit down or take a break, then do so. The yoga instructor should create a vibe where you feel comfortable enough to remove yourself when you need to do so. If they don’t, vote with your feet and find one that does. Don’t compete with more advanced practitioners. You don’t want to end up with heat exhaustion.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"> </span></p>
<h3><span style="font-weight: 400;">Towels</span></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Bring two towels with you. One to wipe sweat off and the second, place it under your head to catch dripping sweat. That’s all you need to know!</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"> </span></p>
<h3><span style="font-weight: 400;">Non-Slip Yoga Mat</span></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">It’s a given that you’re going to get really sweaty so the idea of borrowing a yoga mat may not seem all that appealing. Most devotees prefer to bring their own. That way, they can be sure of its cleanliness and can take responsibility for cleaning it after the session.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Slipping and sliding is a real possibility when practising hot yoga. No-one wants to injure themselves in the pursuit of exercise or relaxation. Thankfully, you can now put your mind at rest because Yogi Bare has got your back. We’ve created a range of high-performance non-slip yoga mats, providing superb grip and a 4mm thickness to support the impact on ankles, wrists and knees. For hot yoga, we’d recommend using our lightweight<span> </span></span><a href="https://www.yogi-bare.com/collections/yoga-mats/Teddy" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Teddy Mats</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"><span> </span>with its fantastic grip and super absorbent surface, it can even be popped in the washing machine after class.  </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">When the possibility of slipping and sliding is eradicated, you can fully focus on your yoga practise. It means you can have greater confidence in pose, improved balance and flow, and you’re much more likely to try new poses out. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">All in all, Bikram yoga is a great way to develop your yoga practise. As long as you equip yourself in the right way and take your time to acclimatise to the heat, you can reap the health and wellbeing rewards that so many others have gained from this discipline.</span></p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
</feed>
