<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xml:lang="en-US" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/" xmlns:s="http://jadedpixel.com/-/spec/shopify">
  <id>https://www.yogi-bare.com/blogs/sustainability-diary.atom</id>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.yogi-bare.com/blogs/sustainability-diary"/>
  <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://www.yogi-bare.com/blogs/sustainability-diary.atom"/>
  <title>Yogi Bare USA - Sustainability diary</title>
  <updated>2021-06-01T05:38:33-05:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Yogi Bare USA</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.yogi-bare.com/blogs/sustainability-diary/dear-mother-earth</id>
    <published>2021-06-01T05:38:33-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-01T05:38:34-05:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.yogi-bare.com/blogs/sustainability-diary/dear-mother-earth"/>
    <title>Dear Mother Earth</title>
    <author>
      <name>Kat Pither</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<div class="rte">
<h6><strong><span>Entry Two. March 2021. </span></strong></h6>
<br><span>Nothing is created. Nothing Disappears. Everything is just transformed. This is the first law of thermodynamics. That all matter, all energy, all things that exist simply shape shift. Nothing is ever destroyed, nothing ever actually disappears. How bonkers is that when you actually take a moment to think about it? Us Yogi’s speak a lot about the shifting of energy and a more esoteric experience of the universe and energy exchange but lets take it back to science for now. </span><br><span>  </span><br><span>Moreover lets take the conceptual out of the universe for a moment. We live on this planet full of matter of varying composition and origin, from plants to sand to minerals to metals. None of which actually disappears. It only shape shifts. Okay, got it. </span><br><span>  </span><br><span>So now let's get into the science of sustainability because facts are something that cannot be argued with or denied. In order to do so we need to be able to define what “Sustainability” actually means. And this was our first stumbling block. </span><br><br><span>We put this question to you, our incredible community (we love the fact you always want to get involved in our explorations!) and our team. Each answer was similar, yet different, a multitude of perspectives and hierarchy of importance. Some were opposing. Some were vague. Some we tried to dig a little deeper on, for example “Sustainable = eco friendly” but what does “eco friendly” mean to you? </span><br><span>It became apparent quite quickly that sustainability is not clear cut. And we were not alone in this. One of the leading figureheads in the sustainability movement Karl Henrik Robert was frustrated at lack of common language around this subject and noted that without understanding the root cause how could we ever create progressive change?  In 1989, he circulated a paper on sustainability to 50 scientists, asking for their input. The extensive deliberative process involved 22 versions, but a consensus emerged that led to The Natural Step. The Natural Step framework sets out the </span><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Natural_Step#Framework">system conditions for sustainability</a><span>, as well as guidelines to systematically approach compliance with the principles.  The Natural Step aims to be both scientifically based and readily understandable in its articulation of principles for sustainability.</span>
<p><br><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/2128/0363/files/5.png?v=1616522019"></p>
<span>Phew no wonder we are all a bit lost at sea in this! If it took 50 scientists, 22 drafts to come to agreement then its okay to find the field of sustainability difficult to navigate. Unfortunately this leaves the space wide open to misinformation, to projecting what maybe a brand wants you too see rather than reality, to putting your best foot forward and leaving the sock-less, shoe with a hole in somewhat in the shadows. </span><br><span>So as a brand we have decided to take a stand. Like we said in post one, when we began Yogi Bare we were operating on the knowledge on sustainable materials and process that was out there readily available to research. Every day more and more brands are emerging echoing this information, thus perpetuating the chain. So in sharing our progress, our knowledge and discoveries openly and transparently we actually hope, implore you to STEAL THESE NOTES. Very banksy I know. But that how change on mass happens. </span><br><span>Sustainability is commonly understood to require the balanced pursuit of three goals: ecological health, social equity, and economic welfare. These were all reflected in your answers to us and simplified: PEOPLE, PLANET, ECONOMY = FUTURE.</span>
<div><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/2128/0363/files/6.png?v=1616522053" alt=""></div>
<p>It is grounded on the ethical commitment to the well-being not only of contemporary populations but also the well- being and enhanced opportunities of future generations. The scientific and technical professions have a special responsibility in this regard because the knowledge and technologies they develop and employ have immense impacts on natural environments, economies, and the empowerment of citizens and societies. Moreover, their efforts and achievements can continue to produce effects, for good or ill, well into the future.</p>
<p>However the nitty gritty of this as a small or any business is rift with complexities. As my personal hero and founder of Patagonia Yvon Chouinard states “Everything man does creates more harm than good. We have to accept that fact and not delude ourselves into thinking something is sustainable. Then you can try to achieve a situation where you’re causing the least amount of harm possible. That’s the spin we put on it. It’s a never-ending summit. You’re just climbing forever.”</p>
<p>As daunting as this statement was as a business owner, within the honesty and factuality was a sense of peace. It made me realise our first steps loud and clear:</p>
<p> </p>
<ol>
<li>
<p>Define our guiding light principles for every business decision moving forward.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Audit our entire range and create a Good/Better/Best time line towards shifting everything in line with our research and guiding principles. No matter the price. No matter the cost.</p>
</li>
</ol>
<p>We were all in.</p>
<p>The best known definition of sustainability is the one stated in the thesis Our Common Future, more commonly known as the Brundtland Report: “..meeting the needs of the present without compromising the ability of future generations to meet their needs.” The whole document boils down to the fact that this is our responsibility of our society to make good choices in order to preserve, protect and restore our resources and environment for the future. We cannot be selfish now and must recognise our role in this. Maybe this in the true meaning of life? We are the trustees and caretakers of the planet for a given amount of time before we hand on to the next generation – alongside sharing our knowledge, our mistakes and our solutions. Some papers state this and requires enormous changes in thinking, policy, and basic assumptions about the economy for its full implementation. But for me it all boils down to honesty, transparency and communication. We are all interdependent, so come on guys less of the greenwashing, less of the competition over community in this. Change and eco consciousness isn’t a game of who shouts loudest about the good, its about how we create solutions for the bad. Why? Because while its not the sexiest, most Instagram friendly thing – it’s the right thing to do.</p>
<p>So heres my line in the sand; </p>
<p> </p>
<h3>Part One, the manifesto.</h3>
<h3>Yogi Bare’s Internal Manifesto and commitment to a sustainable future:</h3>
<ol>
<li>
<p>Sustainability is at the top of every meeting agenda</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>We will continuously audit, challenge and seek alternatives for or remove materials  within our current range by 2024. </p>
</li>
<li>
<p>We will challenge and ask any new retailers or studios about their commitment to sustainability. If they need guidance in their journey we will help them. This goes beyond our range. We will advise them and educate in any means necessary.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Any new product development will have sustainability at its core. If it cannot live up to our self imposed standards we will not proceed until it can.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>We will share and document all changes, learnings and our personal journey to help others and be transparent within our community.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>We will always be open and not use alienating terminology in conveying our messages. Learning should be accessible and our doors will always be open to questions and challenges.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>We aim to implement closed loop processes.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Sustainability isn’t just in the manufacturing and process of creation. We will always look to solutions and repurposing of existing products within the yoga industry – ours and others.</p>
</li>
</ol>
<p>Until next time,</p>
<p>Kat. Founder Yogi Bare. </p>
</div>
<div data-permalink="https://www.yogi-bare.co.uk/blogs/sustainability-diary/sustainability-diary"></div>
<hr>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.yogi-bare.com/blogs/sustainability-diary/sustainability-diary</id>
    <published>2021-06-01T05:37:49-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-01T05:37:50-05:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.yogi-bare.com/blogs/sustainability-diary/sustainability-diary"/>
    <title>Sustainability Diary</title>
    <author>
      <name>Kat Pither</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<h4><strong>Entry One. March 2021.</strong></h4>
<p><em>Dear Mother Earth,</em> </p>
<p><span>Nothing is created. Nothing disappears. Everything is just transformed.</span></p>
<p><span>As part of Yogi Bare’s Year Of The Self it was imperative to us to explore the concept Self Education, especially in regards to sustainability.</span></p>
<p><span>When Yogi Bare was just a little dream, a few scribbles in a notebook, a big idea and a gut instinct our world looked a little different. Five years ago vegan supermarket shopping meant tinned chickpeas and if you were lucky a choice of two (two!) bean burgers in the freezer aisle. The conversations around BLM and institutionalised racism that rocked and reshaped our world were still muted. It was only the beginning of recognising strength in vulnerability and honesty around normalising mental health and breaking down stigma and shame. Fast fashion was in its prime. And sustainability? Well didn’t that just mean using a keep cup and a bit of recycling?</span></p>
<p><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/2128/0363/files/2.png?v=1616521860"></p>
<p><span></span><span>When Yogi Bare began I used all the information available to me at the time to cultivate a brand that echoed my own sensibilities and belief systems – that we only get one planet and we must take care of it. There really is no planet B despite what the sci fi films tell us. We have become so disconnected and our values have become led so far astray that I wanted to help bridge the gap by launching an eco conscious and more accessible yoga brand – mainly because it never made sense to me that we would practice presence, love and connection to our relationship with the earth through yoga while usually sitting on a toxic plastic or PVC mat. Bonkers right? So I researched, asked all the “right” questions, used all the materials and manufacturing information out there to begin Yogi Bare. Back then Yogi Bare was born on a shoestring self funded budget (and if you know me personally you know im not a saver!) and my own naively self education around product, design and starting a business. No external investment, advisor or mentorship (I didn’t even know these things existed beyond Dragons Den) back then. So I went into with a good heart, good intentions and big ideas and looking around the industry we were all operating from the same vibe and same materials. I was doing it! Right?</span><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/2128/0363/files/3.png?v=1616521893">Well now I’m five years deep into Yogi Bare and everything feels a little different. I am so proud to be part of this brave new world where we ask questions, where we fearlessly shout our beliefs and values, where we challenge the status quo and share information and opinions. And we aren’t afraid to expect and demand more from the brands we choose to align with, after all we vote with our pound. And as a small business it is my duty to make your vote count and mean something if you choose Yogi Bare.</p>
<p><span>Yogi Bare has been a very step by step, slow progression behind the scenes. I wish I started a diary much earlier but the Cliff Notes is – I have a vision and innovative ideas for where I would like the brand to be by 2023 and have been making the steps to get there since day one.</span></p>
<p><span>Last year we went through a rebranding due to a trademark dispute with a global brand (but that’s another story for another day hey!) but it gave us a chance to take stock and totally revaluate our packaging as we rebranded it. We were using a recycled and recyclable plastic but it wasn’t clear and the community often commented on how it just didn’t feel Yogi Bare. We’ve finally gone fully plastic free on our packaging – Ill tell ya how a little later.  But it really got me hung up on plastics and misconceptions and the lack of clarity around sustainability. I thought our previous choice was the best choice – protecting the product and the planet somewhat. But with a little education and exploration we did better. So what if I kept educated? Kept doing better? It’s a bold move for a brand who has built a reputation around caring for people and planet to say “hey we didn’t quite get it right. That wasn’t as good as it could have been”. But that’s the only way change happens right. To be a change maker is to get really uncomfortable and shine a lamp and interrogate yourself completely. You’ve gotta take the emotion out of it and work from the facts. Because if nothing changes, nothing moves. Im tired  In an age of transparency and awareness and not accepting less than your best efforts.</span><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/2128/0363/files/4.png?v=1616521950">My friends this is why I have been a little off grid, a little preoccupied. This is probably the most important month of the Self to me. I have been squirrelled away for months, unlearning everything, unpicking everything to relearn. To Self Educate. Because once you begin the process of educating yourself, nothing can ever be unseen.</p>
<p><span>Sustainability is something so close to my heart. How can it not be? I flinch when I see the devastation of industrial practice on our planet. I’m incredibly lucky to be growing within this community, our community, of like minded humans who stand up for and talk about these things that matter so much to us. Its just, it’s a complicated world isn’t it? The world of sustainability isn’t clear cut, sadly within the realm there’s manipulation and smoke and mirrors. There’s misinformation. There’s information with make up on to hide the truth pimples. And then there’s total lack of information in other areas. So we decided to make a stand. Its scary but im putting myself on the line and opening the doors wide open with Yogi Bare and inviting you into the process.</span></p>
<p><span>And if I didn’t truly understand and have it sussed how could I expect our team or community? I realised it was vital to document all of this. Not just to provide a place for people to educate themselves but maybe spark a match within the industry.  Im not precious. In sharing my learning I actually hope that other brands pick up on it and we cause a major shift. For that is where the true change, the only change, is going to happen. From a place of honest transparency. Plus you know i've always had a thing for rebels.</span></p>
<p><em><span>All my love,</span></em></p>
<p><em><span>Kat. Founder of Yogi Bare. </span></em></p>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.yogi-bare.com/blogs/sustainability-diary/may-we-grow-together-may-we-flow-together</id>
    <published>2021-06-01T05:36:28-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-01T05:36:28-05:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.yogi-bare.com/blogs/sustainability-diary/may-we-grow-together-may-we-flow-together"/>
    <title>May we grow together. May we flow together.</title>
    <author>
      <name>Kat Pither</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<h4>This page will hold the notes of our fully transparent sustainability diary. This is a living document which will constantly evolve over time in our commitment to be an open doors brand. Brands, we implore you to steal these ideas and make them your own in order to disrupt the industry and invoke real change. Everything we learn. Every experiment. Every learning. Every desire and goal. They will all live here. Because this is how change happens. Through openness and honesty.</h4>
<div style="text-align: center;"><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/2128/0363/files/Yogi-Bare-website-icons-14_240x240.png?v=1619726148" style="float: none;" width="240x240" height="240x240"></div>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.yogi-bare.com/blogs/sustainability-diary/yogi-bare-s-sustainability-audit</id>
    <published>2021-06-01T05:35:13-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-01T05:35:14-05:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.yogi-bare.com/blogs/sustainability-diary/yogi-bare-s-sustainability-audit"/>
    <title>Yogi Bare’s Sustainability Audit</title>
    <author>
      <name>Kat Pither</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p>Everything we learn. Every experiment. Every learning. Every desire and goal.</p>
<p>In March we showed you some truths about Yogi Bare and our sustainability journey. Through sharing our learning, research and knowledge we hope to be truly transparent with our community and allow you to see the stages of transition and progression throughout the entire process. This living document will evolve over time in our commitment to be open doors.</p>
<p>At the start of 2021, we created an internal sustainability audit to measure where we are, where we want to be and what we can do better. Year upon year the industry is changing, so we should too. We internally researched our materials, processes, products, transparency, packaging and logistics and we aim to better all aspects of the business in an ongoing journey.</p>
<div style="text-align: center;"><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/2128/0363/files/pet-19.12.19_480x480.jpg?v=1621240360" alt="" style="float: none;"></div>
<p><strong><em>Where we are in 2021</em></strong></p>
<p>The discovery of RPET! We saw plastic bottles being turned into clothes and packaging and thought if they can do that, we can create the worlds first RPET yoga stretch strap (recycled polyethylene terephthalate = recycled plastic bottles). Production of RPET lowers carbon emissions by 24% compared to virgin plastics and prevents these plastics ending up in landfill. We aren’t claiming we have solved the plastic crises but we are giving plastic a second life whilst driving awareness and demand.</p>
<p>Our have changed all of our packaging to 100% plastic free. We use FSC cardboard which contains recycled content and always encourage our customers to <em>recycle and reuse</em>. We also reuse returned Magic Carpet Boxes when possible because not only cats get nine lives!</p>
<div style="text-align: center;"><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/2128/0363/files/1_ylgX6KSIiIsk8XVMgDMIqw_480x480.png?v=1621240485" alt="" style="float: none;"></div>
<p>We proudly donate proceeds from our mats to some amazing charities including Hometree Ireland, Sea Shepard and The Wave Project. Recently, we have decided to donate profits from sales to Give India during this time of need. Our recent launch of Downward Duck yoga blocks were a charitable collaboration with Ocean Sole whose mission is to clean up the waterways of Kenya and turn old flip flops into works of art.</p>
<div style="text-align: center;"><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/2128/0363/files/hometree_480x480.jpg?v=1621240741" alt="" style="float: none;"></div>
<p>We create products with purpose that are made of natural, non-harmful or toxic materials. Our research and development made us realise we can do better. We are reassessing each product individually and developing a 12 month plan.</p>
<div style="text-align: center;"><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/2128/0363/files/4_1a54afff-bbb0-4473-8c99-98a5070c036b_480x480.png?v=1621240894" alt="" style="float: none;"></div>
<p>We have a transparent and close net supply chain to ensure all ethical, sustainable and social protocols are achieved for our product and workers. Yogi Bare employs team members in China to run all production and we work closely to ensure warehouse audits and workers rights are met. We use freight by water to reduce our carbon emission.</p>
<p><strong><em>Where are we heading? </em></strong></p>
<p>We aim to continue producing rad, innovative and beautiful yoga mats and equipment for you with true transparency into the how and why. We want our rebels to be using the best possible equipment with the least detrimental impact to the planet.</p>
<p>We are working towards an eco-acupressure mat that does not use foam or coconut coir as both can be detrimental to the planet. We found that coconut coir production takes months and is usually achieved from cheap labour through a process that is dusty and bad for workers health. The natural coconut fibres are cleaned with toxic chemicals and then glued together and toxic chemical buffering is required which takes 300-600 litres of water to wash one cubic metre of coir path. We understand the importance of research and patience and hope to find a better alternative.</p>
<p>We are devoting time to become a more circular economy by repurposing mats at the end of their life and giving them a new lease of life.</p>
<p>We understand that PU leather (the top of our yoga mats) contains hermoplastics. Whilst PU is not a damaging material, we know we can do better so we are finding a completely natural alternative.</p>
<p>Sustainability is at the top of every meeting agenda with the drive to do better for people and planet. We welcome any advice, conversations and learnings. We are reassessing some of our materials and have some exciting projects in the pipeline this year that we can’t WAIT to share! We will be using these sustainability diary posts to keep those of you interested informed and up to date.</p>
<p>Steal these ideas. I’m not daring you, I’m asking you because this is how change happens. Through openness and honesty.</p>
<p><em>May we grow together. May we flow together. </em></p>
<p>Love, Yogi Bare x</p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.yogi-bare.com/blogs/sustainability-diary/understanding-yoga-mat-materials-pu-vs-pvc</id>
    <published>2021-06-01T04:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-21T03:42:46-05:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.yogi-bare.com/blogs/sustainability-diary/understanding-yoga-mat-materials-pu-vs-pvc"/>
    <title>Understanding Yoga Mat Materials: PU vs PVC</title>
    <author>
      <name>Kat Pither</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p>Many moons ago our fellow yogi brothers and sisters developed a yoga mat to prevent them slipping and sliding when they practiced. The cheapest, most accessible material at the time was Polyvinyl Chloride (PVC), a synthetic plastic polymer which we now understand to be extremely harmful for the planet. The material contains cadmium, chlorine, lead and mercury and production causes harmful dioxins and uses highly toxic chlorine. Dioxins can cause reproductive, developmental and immune issues which interfere with hormones and cause cancer and if that wasn’t enough, Greenpeace described PVC as ‘the single most damaging type of plastic’. Devastatingly, over 40 tonnes of PVC are produced every year and many yoga mats and accessories are still made from this material.</p>
<p>Polyurethane (PU) is a much greener alternative to PVC, both in production and after-care. It does not require the same highly toxic chemical plasticizer and is degradable over time. It has extremely high-performance qualities, has the ultimate grip and is breathable which is why we use it as the top of our yoga mats over the natural rubber non-slip base. Although PU is better, many yoga brands are claiming it to be completely sustainable when it is not. We know we can do better and are currently searching for a more conscious material.</p>
<p>Vegan leathers like PU are increasingly popular and used to make bags, shoes, tesla car seats, wallets and the top of many yoga mats including Yogi Bares. Ongoing innovations have resulted in developing plant-based leathers such as apple, banana, pineapple and field corn which is carbon neutral however, these are extremely expensive to produce and until demand increases and the materials becoming more affordable, they cannot easily replace PU. Any vegan leather requires a plastic protective coating for durability which has many issues of its own.  </p>
<p>Because polyurethanes like PU are<span> </span><a href="https://www.polyurethanes.org/en/what-is-it/science-research">petrochemical-based polymers</a>, it is important that we recycle them whenever possible, so that precious raw materials do not go to waste. In standard landfill conditions our yoga mats are expected to break down within 5 years which is why we are developing ways at Yogi Bare to offer our mats a second life that isn’t landfill (we will explore biodegradability in an upcoming diary post)  </p>
<p>There are many long, unrelatable terms in yogi land and we just wanted to break down the difference in these materials and be fully transparent in our understanding that PU is better, but not the best.</p>
<p>With Love,</p>
<p>Yogi Bare x</p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
</feed>
